<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5.dtd">
<ep-patent-document id="EP17001379A1" file="EP17001379NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3441030" kind="A1"
    date-publ="20190213" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5">
    <SDOBI lang="en">
        <B000>
            <eptags>
                <B001EP>
                    ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMA....MD..........
                </B001EP>
                <B005EP>J</B005EP>
                <B007EP>BDM Ver 0.1.63 (23 May 2017) - 1100000/0</B007EP>
                <B053EP>Amended claims in accordance with Rule 137(2) EPC.</B053EP>
            </eptags>
        </B000>
        <B100>
            <B110>3441030</B110>
            <B120>
                <B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121>
            </B120>
            <B130>A1</B130>
            <B140>
                <date>20190213</date>
            </B140>
            <B190>EP</B190>
        </B100>
        <B200>
            <B210>17001379.1</B210>
            <B220>
                <date>20170811</date>
            </B220>
            <B240>
                <B241>
                    <date>20181218</date>
                </B241>
            </B240>
            <B250>en</B250>
            <B251EP>en</B251EP>
            <B260>en</B260>
        </B200>
        <B400>
            <B405>
                <date>20190213</date>
                <bnum>201907</bnum>
            </B405>
            <B430>
                <date>20190213</date>
                <bnum>201907</bnum>
            </B430>
        </B400>
        <B500>
            <B510EP>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>A61B 17/80 20060101AFI20180208BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>A61B 17/88 20060101ALI20180208BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
            </B510EP>
            <B540>
                <B541>de</B541>
                <B542>VERFORMBARE KRANIALE FRÄSBOHRPLATTE UND VERFORMUNGSINSTRUMENT DAFÜR</B542>
                <B541>en</B541>
                <B542>DEFORMABLE CRANIAL BURR HOLE PLATE AND DEFORMATION INSTRUMENT THEREFOR</B542>
                <B541>fr</B541>
                <B542>PLAQUE DE TROU FRAISÉ CRÂNIENNE DÉFORMABLE ET INSTRUMENT DE DÉFORMATION CORRESPONDANT</B542>
            </B540>
            <B590>
                <B598>1A</B598>
            </B590>
        </B500>
        <B700>
            <B710>
                <B711>
                    <snm>Stryker European Holdings I, LLC</snm>
                    <iid>101518673</iid>
                    <irf>EPA-138 568</irf>
                    <adr>
                        <str>2825 Airview Boulevard</str>
                        <city>Kalamazoo, MI 49002</city>
                        <ctry>US</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B711>
            </B710>
            <B720>
                <B721>
                    <snm>Kuhn, Sven Martin</snm>
                    <adr>
                        <str>Schorenweg 10</str>
                        <city>79312 Emmendingen</city>
                        <ctry>DE</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B721>
            </B720>
            <B740>
                <B741>
                    <snm>Röthinger, Rainer</snm>
                    <iid>101205746</iid>
                    <adr>
                        <str>Wuesthoff &amp; Wuesthoff
                            Patentanwälte PartG mbB
                            Schweigerstrasse 2</str>
                        <city>81541 München</city>
                        <ctry>DE</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B741>
            </B740>
        </B700>
        <B800>
            <B840>
                <ctry>AL</ctry>
                <ctry>AT</ctry>
                <ctry>BE</ctry>
                <ctry>BG</ctry>
                <ctry>CH</ctry>
                <ctry>CY</ctry>
                <ctry>CZ</ctry>
                <ctry>DE</ctry>
                <ctry>DK</ctry>
                <ctry>EE</ctry>
                <ctry>ES</ctry>
                <ctry>FI</ctry>
                <ctry>FR</ctry>
                <ctry>GB</ctry>
                <ctry>GR</ctry>
                <ctry>HR</ctry>
                <ctry>HU</ctry>
                <ctry>IE</ctry>
                <ctry>IS</ctry>
                <ctry>IT</ctry>
                <ctry>LI</ctry>
                <ctry>LT</ctry>
                <ctry>LU</ctry>
                <ctry>LV</ctry>
                <ctry>MC</ctry>
                <ctry>MK</ctry>
                <ctry>MT</ctry>
                <ctry>NL</ctry>
                <ctry>NO</ctry>
                <ctry>PL</ctry>
                <ctry>PT</ctry>
                <ctry>RO</ctry>
                <ctry>RS</ctry>
                <ctry>SE</ctry>
                <ctry>SI</ctry>
                <ctry>SK</ctry>
                <ctry>SM</ctry>
                <ctry>TR</ctry>
            </B840>
            <B844EP>
                <B845EP>
                    <ctry>BA</ctry>
                </B845EP>
                <B845EP>
                    <ctry>ME</ctry>
                </B845EP>
            </B844EP>
            <B848EP>
                <B849EP>
                    <ctry>MA</ctry>
                </B849EP>
                <B849EP>
                    <ctry>MD</ctry>
                </B849EP>
            </B848EP>
        </B800>
    </SDOBI>
    <abstract id="abst" lang="en">
        <p id="pa01" num="0001">A cranial burr hole plate and a deformation instrument are provided. The burr hole plate
            comprises a plate body and a plurality of spikes extending from the plate body that are configured to engage
            cranial bone. The burr hole plate is deformable to enable movement of the spikes from a burr hole
            disengaging configuration to a burr hole engaging configuration upon deformation of the burr hole plate. The
            deformation instrument is configured for moving the spikes of a cranial burr hole plate into the burr hole
            engaging configuration.
            <img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="85" he="108" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" /></p>
    </abstract>
    <description id="desc" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
        <heading id="h0001"><b>Technical Field</b></heading>
        <p id="p0001" num="0001">The present disclosure generally relates to surgical implants. In particular, a plate
            for covering a cranial burr hole and an instrument for fixing the implant to cranial bone are presented.</p>
        <heading id="h0002"><b>Background</b></heading>
        <p id="p0002" num="0002">Surgery for treating intracranial diseases often involves drilling a burr hole into the
            skull of a patient to obtain access to the intracranial region. In order to close the burr hole after the
            intracranial treatment, a plate covering the burr hole is then fixed to the cranial bone. To this end,
            conventional burr hole plates comprise screw openings to receive fixation screws that are screwed into the
            cranial bone.</p>
        <p id="p0003" num="0003">Screwing the screws into the cranial bone is time-consuming and leads to longer surgery
            times. Furthermore, the utilized screws are expensive due to strict surgical requirements like
            biocompatibility and sterility.</p>
        <heading id="h0003"><b>Summary</b></heading>
        <p id="p0004" num="0004">There is a need for a burr hole plate that can more easily be attached to cranial bone.
        </p>
        <p id="p0005" num="0005">According to one aspect, a cranial plate for covering a burr hole is provided that
            comprises a plate body and a plurality of spikes extending from the plate body. The spikes are configured to
            engage cranial bone, wherein the plate is deformable to enable movement of the spikes from a disengaging
            configuration to an engaging configuration upon deformation of the plate.</p>
        <p id="p0006" num="0006">At least part of the cranial burr hole plate may be formed from a biocompatible
            material like titanium, nitinol or titanium nitride. At least a portion of the cranial burr
            <!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> hole plate may be covered by a bio-compatible material. Moreover, at least a portion
            of the cranial burr hole plate may be bio-resorbable.</p>
        <p id="p0007" num="0007">The plate body of the burr hole plate may be deformable. The plate body may have a burr
            hole covering portion. The burr hole covering portion may have one or more openings, or may not have any
            openings. The burr hole plate may be deformable by applying a force onto the burr hole covering portion. As
            such, at least the burr hole covering portion of the plate body may be deformable. The applied force may
            have an axial and/or downward direction with respect to the cranium.</p>
        <p id="p0008" num="0008">At least a part of the plate body, such as the burr hole covering portion, may be
            configured to assume one of a convex form with a positive curvature, a flat form with zero curvature and a
            concave form with a negative curvature when the spikes are in a burr hole disengaging configuration. As an
            example, the burr hole covering portion may be one of convex, flat or concave. The plate body may be
            deformable in such a manner that the plate body assumes a form with a decreased curvature when the spikes
            are in a burr hole engaging configuration. A decreased curvature may comprise deforming the plate body form
            from a convex form to a flat form, a convex form to a concave form, a flat form to a concave form, a convex
            form to a less convex form or a concave form to a more concave form.</p>
        <p id="p0009" num="0009">The plate body may be essentially plastically deformable. The plate body may comprise
            areas with varying degrees of deformability. The plate body may be more deformable at radially outer areas
            compared to radially inner areas. The plate body may have areas with a reduced wall thickness that are
            configured to be more deformable. A plastically deformable plate body may, for example, be made from grade 2
            or lower grade titanium.</p>
        <p id="p0010" num="0010">The plate body may in another variant be essentially elastically deformable. An
            elastically deformable plate body may, for example, be made from grade 4 or higher grade titanium.</p>
        <p id="p0011" num="0011">Furthermore, the elastically deformable plate body may have a bistable configuration
            with (at least) two stable states. The plate body may have different curvatures in the two stable states, as
            explained above. The plate body may be configured to bias the spikes into the engaging configuration when
            elastically deformed.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="3"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0012" num="0012">The tip of one or more of the spikes may have an essentially triangular shape with a
            wall thickness similar to that of the plate body. Therefore, such spikes may have an improved structural
            strength that supports maintaining the engaging configuration. Alternatively, the wall thickness of one or
            more of the spikes may decrease in a direction towards the tip. Therefore that tip may have a smaller
            contacting surface on the burr hole wall and exert a higher pressure. One or more of the spikes may have a
            plurality of tips. Moreover, one or more of the spikes may have a roughened surface at their sides facing
            cranial bone.</p>
        <p id="p0013" num="0013">At least one of the spikes may be configured to contact a burr hole wall when the
            plurality of spikes is in the engaging configuration. The at least one of the spikes may be configured to
            contact at least one of an outer cortical layer, a diploë and an inner cortical layer of the burr hole wall,
            and, thus, the burr hole.</p>
        <p id="p0014" num="0014">The plate body may comprise a hub and spokes. The spokes may extend from the hub. The
            spokes may have the same length or different lengths.</p>
        <p id="p0015" num="0015">The plate body may comprise a circumferential ring. The circumferential ring may be
            configured to contact a cranial bone surface. The circumferential ring may have an essentially circular,
            elliptical or polygonal form. The circumferential ring may have at least one recess extending from an outer
            rim of the ring towards the center. The circumferential ring may further be configured to support at least a
            part of the plurality of spikes. The spikes may extend from an inner rim of the circumferential ring. If the
            plate comprises a hub and spokes, the spokes may extend from the hub to the circumferential ring.
            Alternatively, or in addition, the spikes may extend from the spokes.</p>
        <p id="p0016" num="0016">The plate body may comprise an alignment feature to align the plate body with a
            deformation instrument. The alignment feature may further comprise at least one opening in the plate body
            for inserting a portion of the deformation instrument into the opening. The alignment feature may be
            disposed at a geometric center of the plate body or spaced apart therefrom.</p>
        <p id="p0017" num="0017">The cranial burr hole plate may be formed in one piece. The cranial burr hole plate may
            be formed from a metal sheet. The cranial burr hole plate may be formed by (e.g., laser) cutting and/or
            bending processes. The cranial burr hole plate may have a thickness of ca. 0.1 to 1.5 mm (e.g., of ca. 0.2
            to 0.6 mm).
            <!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0018" num="0018">The plate body may have a bone facing side. In such a case the plurality of spikes may
            extend from the bone facing side of the plate body.</p>
        <p id="p0019" num="0019">According to a second aspect, a deformation instrument for moving the spikes of a
            cranial plate into the engaging configuration is provided. The deformation instrument comprises a radially
            outer sleeve and a radially inner stamp disposed inside the radially outer sleeve and axially movable
            thereto. The stamp is configured to deform the plate upon application of an axial force on the stamp.</p>
        <p id="p0020" num="0020">The stamp may comprise an actuation element on an end of the stamp. The stamp may be
            elastically biased away from the sleeve. Operation of the stamp may require overcoming the elastic bias.</p>
        <p id="p0021" num="0021">The stamp may comprise a first stamp portion and a second stamp portion, wherein the
            first stamp portion is concentric to the second stamp portion. The first stamp portion may be configured to
            deform the plate body of the burr hole plate and the second stamp portion may be configured to deform the
            spikes of the burr hole plate.</p>
        <p id="p0022" num="0022">The deformation instrument may comprise an alignment feature configured to engage the
            complementary alignment feature of the plate body. The alignment feature may be disposed on the stamp and/or
            the sleeve. The alignment feature may comprise a protrusion, such as a pin.</p>
        <p id="p0023" num="0023">According to a third aspect, a cranial plating system is provided. The system comprises
            the cranial plate and the deformation instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0024" num="0024">According to a fourth aspect, a method for closing a cranial burr hole is disclosed.
            The method comprises placing a deformable plate onto the burr hole, wherein the plate comprises a plate body
            and a plurality of spikes extending from the plate body. The method further comprises deforming the burr
            hole plate to move the spikes from a disengaging configuration to an engaging configuration in which the
            spikes engage cranial bone.</p>
        <p id="p0025" num="0025">The step of deforming the burr hole plate may be performed by applying an axial force
            on the burr hole plate by a stamp of a deformation instrument.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="5"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0004"><b>Brief Description of the Drawings</b></heading>
        <p id="p0026" num="0026">Further details, advantages and aspects of the present disclosure will become apparent
            from the following embodiments taken in conjunction with the drawings, wherein:
            <dl id="dl0001">
                <dt>Fig. 1A</dt>
                <dd>shows a perspective top view of an embodiment of a cranial burr hole plate;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 1B</dt>
                <dd>shows a perspective bottom view of the embodiment of the cranial burr hole plate of <figref
                        idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 2</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of the cranial burr hole plate of <figref
                        idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> in a burr hole disengaging configuration disposed in a
                    burr hole;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 3</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of the cranial burr hole plate of <figref
                        idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> in a burr hole engaging configuration disposed in a burr
                    hole;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 4A</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of the cranial burr hole plate of <figref
                        idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> engaging an outer cortical layer;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 4B</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of the cranial burr hole plate of <figref
                        idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> engaging a diploë layer;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 5A</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of a first embodiment of a deformation instrument;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 5B</dt>
                <dd>shows a perspective view of a bottom surface of the first embodiment of the deformation instrument
                    in <figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref>;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 6A</dt>
                <dd>shows a side view of a second embodiment of a deformation instrument;</dd>
                <dt>Fig. 6B</dt>
                <dd>shows a cross-sectional view of the second embodiment of a deformation instrument along the line A-A
                    in <figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6A</figref>; and
                    <!-- EPO <DP n="6"> -->
                </dd>
                <dt>Fig. 6C</dt>
                <dd>shows an enlarged cross-sectional view of the bottom of the second embodiment of a deformation
                    instrument.</dd>
            </dl>
        </p>
        <heading id="h0005"><b>Detailed Description</b></heading>
        <p id="p0027" num="0027">In the following description, exemplary embodiments of a deformable cranial burr hole
            plate and deformation instrument therefor will be explained with reference to the drawings. The same or
            similar reference numerals will be used to denote the same or similar structural features.</p>
        <p id="p0028" num="0028">
            <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref> shows a perspective top view of an embodiment of a cranial burr hole
            plate 10. The burr hole plate 10 comprises a plate body 12 and a plurality of spikes 14 extending from the
            plate body 12. In the embodiment shown, there are eight spikes 14 extending from the plate body 12. It
            should be appreciated that a different number of spikes could be provided (e.g., three to twelve). In the
            state of the burr hole plate 10 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>, the spikes 14 are in
            a burr hole disengaging configuration. In the present state, spikes 14 are in other words in a neutral
            configuration.
        </p>
        <p id="p0029" num="0029">The plate body 12 comprises a circumferential ring 16 with a plurality of recesses 18.
            In the embodiment shown, there are four recesses 18 extending from the plate body 12. The recesses 18 extend
            from an outer rim of the ring 16 towards its center and enable gripping of the cranial burr hole plate 10 in
            a torque proof manner. It should be appreciated that a different number of recesses could be provided (e.g.,
            two to eight).</p>
        <p id="p0030" num="0030">The plate body 10 further comprises a plurality of spokes 20 that extend from the
            circumferential ring 16 radially inwardly to a central hub 22. Each spoke 20 lies between adjacent recesses
            18. In the embodiment shown, there are four spokes 20 extending from the circumferential ring 16. Therefore,
            the spokes 20 mechanically connect the circumferential ring 16 with the hub 22.</p>
        <p id="p0031" num="0031">The hub 22 comprises an alignment feature 24 in the form of a circular opening 26. The
            opening 26 is configured to receive a part of a deformation instrument. The opening 26 limits radial
            movement of the deforming instruments and aligns the deforming instrument with the burr hole plate 10.
            Alternatively or additionally, the alignment feature 24 can be located at another location of the burr hole
            plate 10.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="7"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0032" num="0032">The spokes 20 define openings therebetween that allow (e.g., visual) access to
            underlying cranial tissue and to the spikes 14. Alternatively, the plate body 10 may comprise no openings
            for an increased structural strength and better protection of the underlying cranial tissue.</p>
        <p id="p0033" num="0033">The plate body 12 has a convex form. Therefore, the hub 22 extends in a direction away
            from the cranial burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0034" num="0034">
            <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1B</figref> shows a perspective bottom view of the embodiment of the cranial burr
            hole plate 10 with the spikes 14 still in a burr hole disengaging configuration. As illustrated in <figref
                idref="f0001">Fig. 1B</figref>, the eight spikes 14 are combined to define four pairs of two spikes 14.
            The spikes 14 may be combined to groups of different numbers. Alternatively, the spikes 14 may be angularly
            evenly distributed.
        </p>
        <p id="p0035" num="0035">Each spike 14 has a pointed tip that, when biased against the cranial bone material,
            resists movement of the spike 14 relative to the cranial bone material. This can be achieved by at least one
            of friction and forming a dent in the cranial bone material by the tip of the spike 14.</p>
        <p id="p0036" num="0036">The burr hole plate 10 is formed in one piece from a metal sheet. The metal sheet may
            be made from grade 2 titanium so that the burr hole plate 10 is substantially plastically deformable. In
            other embodiments, the burr hole plate 10 may be made from grade 4 titanium and have elastically deformable
            properties. In particular, the burr hole plate 10 may have a bistable configuration such that the plate body
            10 may have different curvatures in the two stable states, as explained above.</p>
        <p id="p0037" num="0037">In the embodiment of <figref idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref>, there are no
            spikes 14 disposed at the spokes 20. Alternatively, or in addition, spikes could extend from the spokes 20.
            The spikes could also be separate elements that are attached to the plate body 12 (e.g. by clamping or
            welding).</p>
        <p id="p0038" num="0038">
            <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of the embodiment of the cranial burr
            hole plate 10 of <figref idref="f0001">Figs. 1A and 1B</figref> in a burr hole neutral or disengaging state
            and disposed in a burr hole 32. The burr hole 32 is disposed in the cranial bone material of a skull 30 and
            has an essentially cylindrical shape with a burr hole wall 34.
        </p>
        <p id="p0039" num="0039">The plate body 12 of the burr hole plate 10 has a bone facing side 28. The spikes 14
            extend from the bone facing side 28 towards the burr hole 32. The bone facing side
            <!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> 28 of the circumferential ring 16 is configured to contact an outer surface of the
            skull 30 in the region adjacent to the burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0040" num="0040">When the cranial burr hole plate 10 is in its burr hole disengaging configuration, the
            plate body 12 has a convex shape, wherein the hub 22 extends out of a base plane 17 in a direction away from
            the cranial burr hole 32. The base plane 17 is defined by the upper rim of the burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0041" num="0041">In the embodiment illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the hub 22 is
            spaced from the base plane 17 by ca. 0.7 mm. The hub may generally be spaced from the base plane 17 by a
            different distance between 0.2 mm to 3.0 mm.</p>
        <p id="p0042" num="0042">Alternatively, the plate body 12 may have a flat shape and extend within the base plane
            when the spikes 14 are in the burr hole disengaging configuration. As a further alternative, the plate body
            12 may have a concave shape, wherein the hub 22 is spaced from the base plane 17 towards the inside of the
            cranium.</p>
        <p id="p0043" num="0043">As illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the spikes 14 extend relative
            to the base plane 17 at an angle of 99.6° in their burr hole disengaging configuration. In general the
            spikes 14 may extend relative to the base plane 17 at an angle of approximately 85° to 115° (e.g.,
            approximately 95° to approximately 105°). The angle may vary for each spike 14.</p>
        <p id="p0044" num="0044">
            <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of the cranial burr hole plate 10 in a
            burr hole engaging state and disposed in a burr hole 32. Compared to the burr hole plate 10 shown in <figref
                idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>, the burr hole plate 10 has been elastically deformed from a convex shape
            to a substantially flat shape, so that the hub 22 is disposed in the base plane 17. The deformation has been
            obtained by applying a force on the central region of the burr hole plate 10 (e.g., in the region of the hub
            22 and an adjacent region of the spokes 20).
        </p>
        <p id="p0045" num="0045">For the burr hole engaging configuration, the angle of the extension of the spikes 14
            relative to the base plane 17 increased compared to the burr hole disengaging configuration illustrated in
            <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref>. Specifically, the angle of extension is increased to 101°, so that
            the spikes 14 (more firmly) contact the wall 34 of the burr hole 32. Generally, the angle of extension of
            the spikes 14 may increase by 0.5° to 4° relative to their burr hole disengaging configuration.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="9"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0046" num="0046">Due to a deformation, the radially outer rim of the circumferential ring 16 rotates
            away from the skull 30. The spokes 20 at the radially inner rim thus rotate towards the skull 30. Therefore,
            the spikes 14 also rotate (further) towards wall 34 to assume their burr hole engaging configuration.</p>
        <p id="p0047" num="0047">The deformation is not limited to the example illustrated in <figref idref="f0002">
                Figs. 2</figref> and <figref idref="f0003">3</figref>. In general, the spikes 14 will be in a burr hole
            engaging configuration when the plate body 10 assumes a form with a decreased curvature compared to a form
            of the plate body 10 when the spikes 14 are in their burr hole disengaging configuration.</p>
        <p id="p0048" num="0048">The spikes 14 may contact different layers 36 of the cranial bone material in their
            burr hole engaging configuration as will now be discussed in regard to <figref idref="f0004">Figs. 4A and 4B
            </figref>.</p>
        <p id="p0049" num="0049">
            <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4A</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of the cranial burr hole plate 10
            engaging an outer cortical layer 36a. <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4B</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of
            the cranial burr hole plate 10 engaging a diploë layer 36b. The cranial burr hole plate 10 can also be
            configured to contact an inner cortical layer 36c. The particular bone layer to be contacted by a particular
            spike 14 can be determined by a length and/or angle of that spike 14. A spike 14 can also be configured to
            comprise a plurality of tips, which can contact the same or different cortical layers 36. Two spikes can
            each be configured to contact different cortical layers 36. This advantageously allows asymmetrical designs
            that take into account varying thicknesses of the cortical layers 36.
        </p>
        <p id="p0050" num="0050">
            <figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of an embodiment of a deformation
            instrument 40. The deformation instrument may be employed to deform the cranial burr hole plate 10 from the
            state shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> to the state shown in <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3
            </figref>. Alternatively, this deformation may also be achieved by another type of instrument or by pressing
            on the cranial burr hole plate 10 with a finger of the surgeon's hand.
        </p>
        <p id="p0051" num="0051">The deformation instrument 40 of <figref idref="f0005">Fig. 5A</figref> comprises a
            radially outer sleeve 42 and a radially inner stamp 44. The radially inner stamp 44 is disposed inside the
            radially outer sleeve 42 and is axially movable thereto. The stamp 44 comprises an actuation element 46 with
            a radial extension that exceeds an inner diameter of the sleeve 42 and therefore prevents movement of the
            actuation element 46 into the sleeve 42. The deformation instrument 40 further comprises a spring 48 that
            axially biases the
            <!-- EPO <DP n="10"> --> stamp 44 relative to the sleeve 42. The actuation instrument 40 further comprises
            two handles 50a, 50b for being engaged by the surgeon's fingers.</p>
        <p id="p0052" num="0052">The actuation element 46 and the handles 50a, 50b enable an application of a force that
            moves the stamp 44 axially relative to the sleeve 42 against the bias of the spring 48. In one exemplary
            embodiment, the surgeon presses with a thumb or palm onto the actuation element 46 and pulls on both handles
            50a, 50b with an index finger and a middle finger to control axial movement of the stamp 44 relative to the
            sleeve 42. The stamp 44 has a bottom surface 52 configured to transfer the force that is applied on the
            deformation instrument 40 to the cranial burr hole plate 10.</p>
        <p id="p0053" num="0053">The stamp 44 further comprises an optional alignment feature 54 extending from the
            bottom surface 52. The alignment feature 54 comprises a pin or similar structure. The alignment feature 54
            of the stamp 44 is configured to engage the complementary alignment feature 24 (see the corresponding
            opening in the hub 22 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>) of the plate body 12 of the
            burr hole plate 10. The alignment feature 52 prevents or limits radial movement of the stamp 44 relative to
            the burr hole plate 10, particularly when applying a force onto the stamp 44.</p>
        <p id="p0054" num="0054">During cranial surgery, the surgeon operates the deformation instrument 40 as follows.
        </p>
        <p id="p0055" num="0055">The surgeon first places the cranial burr hole plate 10 onto a burr hole 32 as
            generally shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> and places the deformation instrument 60 on top of
            the burr hole plate 10. At this time, the surgeon inserts the pin of the alignment element 54 into the
            opening of the alignment element 24 of the hub 22.</p>
        <p id="p0056" num="0056">Alternatively, the deformation instrument 40 may comprise an attachment feature (not
            shown) that enables temporary attachment of the burr hole plate 10 to the deformation instrument 40. Once
            the burr hole plate 10 has been picked up by the attachment feature of the deformation instrument 40, the
            surgeon, using the deformation instrument 40, positions the burr hole plate 10 onto the burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0057" num="0057">Initially, the sleeve 42 rests on the circumferential ring 16 and therefore does not
            exert any significant deformation force onto the plate body 12. The surgeon then grips the handles 50a, 50b
            with the index and middle finger and pushes with the thumb or palm onto the actuation element 46. The stamp
            44 transfers the applied force onto the plate body 12, wherein the plate body 12 is deformed in such a way
            <!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> that it assumes a form with a decreased curvature (see <figref idref="f0003">Fig. 3
            </figref>, the deformation instrument 40 has again been omitted).</p>
        <p id="p0058" num="0058">As explained above, due to the resulting deformation, the spikes 14 move from a burr
            hole disengaging configuration to a burr hole engaging configuration. After having deformed the plate body
            12, the surgeon stops applying a force onto the actuation element 46, and the spring 48 biases the stamp 44
            away from the body plate 12. Then, the surgeon removes the deformation instrument 40 from the burr hole
            plate 10.</p>
        <p id="p0059" num="0059">
            <figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6A</figref> shows a side view of a second embodiment of a deformation instrument
            60 and <figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6B</figref> shows a cross-sectional view of the second embodiment of the
            deformation instrument 60 along the line A-A in <figref idref="f0006">Fig. 6A</figref>. <figref
                idref="f0007">Fig. 6C</figref> shows an enlarged cross-sectional view of the bottom of the deformation
            instrument 60. The main differences between the second embodiment and the first embodiment of the
            deformation instrument are a stamp that comprises two concentric stamp portions and stamp protrusions
            extending from stamp fingers of the stamp.
        </p>
        <p id="p0060" num="0060">The deformation instrument 60 illustrated in <figref idref="f0006 f0007">Figs. 6A to 6C
            </figref> comprises a first stamp portion 62, a second stamp portion 64 and an outer sleeve 66. The first
            stamp portion 62 is disposed in a cylindrical opening of the second stamp portion 64 and is axially movable
            thereto, wherein the first stamp portion 62 is axially biased against the second stamp portion 64 by means
            of a first spring 68. A stopping bar 70 extends through a vertically elongated opening in the first stamp
            portion 62 and is mechanically connected with the second stamp portion 64, but not with the outer sleeve 66.
            The stopping bar 70 limits axial movement of the first stamp portion 62 relative to the second stamp portion
            64 and prevents unintended separation of both stamp portions 62, 64.</p>
        <p id="p0061" num="0061">The first stamp portion 62 and the second stamp portion 64 are disposed inside the
            outer sleeve 66. The second stamp portion 64 is axially movable relative to the outer sleeve 66 and axially
            biased relative thereto by means of a second spring 72. The second spring 72 may have a larger spring
            constant than the first spring 68. The second stamp portion 64 is rotationally movable relative to the outer
            sleeve 66.</p>
        <p id="p0062" num="0062">The second stamp portion 64 comprises a handle 74 that allows the surgeon to apply a
            torque to the second stamp portion 64. To that end, the sleeve 66 comprises a handle opening 76. The handle
            74 extends through that handle opening 76. The
            <!-- EPO <DP n="12"> --> handle opening 76 has an L-shape with horizontally and vertically extending
            portions. The horizontal extension of the handle opening 76 enables movement of the handle 74 during
            rotational movement of the second stamp portion 64 relative to the sleeve 66. The vertical extension of the
            handle opening 76 enables movement of the handle 74 during axial movement of the second stamp portion 64
            relative to the sleeve 66.</p>
        <p id="p0063" num="0063">The first stamp portion 62 further comprises an alignment feature 78 extending from the
            bottom of the first stamp 62. The alignment feature 78 comprises a pin or similar structure. The alignment
            feature 78 of the first stamp portion 62 is configured to engage the complementary alignment feature 24 (see
            the corresponding opening in the hub 22 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>) of the plate
            body 12 of the burr hole plate 10. The alignment feature 78 prevents or limits radial movement of the first
            stamp portion 62 relative to the burr hole plate 10, particularly when applying a force onto the first stamp
            portion 62.</p>
        <p id="p0064" num="0064">The second stamp portion 64 comprises a plurality of stamp fingers 80 axially extending
            downwards with a stamp protrusion 84 extending from each lower end of a stamp finger 80. The stamp fingers
            80 are circumferentially separated by slits (not shown) and biased radially outwards against the outer
            sleeve 66. When the second stamp portion 64 is moved axially downwards, the stamp fingers 80 slide along the
            outer sleeve 66. When a tapering 82 of the second stamp portion 64 reaches the bottom of the outer sleeve
            66, the stamp fingers 80 as well as the stamp protrusions 84 move radially outwards due to the radial bias
            of the stamp fingers 80.</p>
        <p id="p0065" num="0065">The stamp protrusions 84 are configured to engage the spikes 14 (see the corresponding
            spikes 14 illustrated in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1A</figref>) from a radially inner side. When the stamp
            protrusions 84 engage the spikes 14 of the burr hole plate 10 and move radially outwards, the bias of the
            stamp fingers 80 exerts a radial force onto the spikes 14, which pushes the spikes 14 (further) outwards.
            For this purpose the surface of the stamp protrusions 84 may be inclined at the spike 14 engaging side in
            such a way that an axial downward movement of the stamp protrusions 84 pushes the spikes 14 that contact the
            inclined surface of the stamp protrusions 84 radially outwards.</p>
        <p id="p0066" num="0066">During cranial surgery, the surgeon operates the deformation instrument 60 as follows.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="13"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0067" num="0067">The surgeon first places the cranial burr hole plate 10 onto a burr hole 32 as
            generally shown in <figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2</figref> and places the deformation instrument 60 on top of
            the burr hole plate 10. When doing this, the surgeon inserts the pin of the alignment feature 78 into the
            opening of the alignment element 24 of the hub 22. Moreover, when placing the deformation instrument 60 on
            top of the burr hole plate 10, the surgeon moves the stamp protrusions 84 through the openings of the burr
            hole plate until they engage the radially inner side of the spikes 14.</p>
        <p id="p0068" num="0068">Alternatively, the deformation instrument 60 may comprise an attachment feature (not
            shown) that enables temporary attachment of the burr hole plate 10 onto the deformation instrument 60. Once
            the burr hole plate 10 has been picked up via the attachment feature, the surgeon, using the deformation
            instrument 60, positions the burr hole plate 10 in the burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0069" num="0069">Then the surgeon applies an axial force onto the top of the first stamp portion 62
            against the bias of the first spring 68. The first stamp portion 62 contacts the burr hole plate 10, wherein
            the force applied by the surgeon deforms the burr hole plate 10 in such a way that it assumes a form with a
            decreased curvature. As explained above, due to the resulting deformation, the spikes 14 move from a burr
            hole disengaging configuration to a burr hole engaging configuration. In the following step, the spikes 14
            are further bent radially outwards in order to improve the engagement between the spikes 14 and the cranial
            burr hole 32.</p>
        <p id="p0070" num="0070">The handle 74 is disposed in the vertically elongated portion of the handle opening 76
            and therefore does not block axial movement of the second stamp portion 64 relative to the sleeve 66. The
            first stamp portion 62 is axially moved to such an extent that the vertical opening of the first stamp
            portion 62 now contacts the top of the stopping bar 70. Therefore, the axial force applied by the surgeon
            onto the first stamp portion 62 is also applied to the second stamp portion 64. In an alternative
            embodiment, the first stamp portion 62 contacts the second stamp portion 64 due to a completely compressed
            first spring 68.</p>
        <p id="p0071" num="0071">The force applied by the surgeon axially moves the second stamp portion 64 relative to
            the outer sleeve 66 until the tapering 82 of the second stamp portion 64 reaches the bottom side of the
            outer sleeve 66. Alternatively, the surgeon may apply an axial force onto the outer sleeve 66 in an upwards
            direction. To this end, the handle opening 76 may comprise another vertical extension that extends
            downwards. The handle opening 76 may, for example, have the shape of a capital T that is rotated
            <!-- EPO <DP n="14"> --> 90° to the side. The second vertical extension of the handle opening 74 may provide
            an increased range for axial movement of the outer sleeve 66 relative to the second stamp portion 64 and
            therefore also relative to the tapering 82.</p>
        <p id="p0072" num="0072">As explained above, due to the tapering 82 and the bias of the second stamp portion 64,
            the stamp fingers 80 exert a force radially against the spikes 14 instead of the outer sleeve 66 when the
            tapering 82 has been moved out of the sleeve 66. Due to this force, the spikes 14 are pushed further into
            the cranial bone, which improves the engagement of the burr hole plate 10 with the cranial burr hole 32. The
            deformation of the burr hole plate 10 is now completed.</p>
        <p id="p0073" num="0073">At this point the surgeon still applies a force onto the first stamp portion 62.
            Therefore, the surgeon rotates the second stamp portion 64 relative to the outer sleeve 66 by horizontally
            rotating the handle 74 into the horizontally elongated portion of the handle opening 76. In this handle
            configuration the handle opening 76 is configured to block axial movement of the handle 74 as well as the
            second stamp portion 64 relative to the outer sleeve 66. Therefore the surgeon can stop applying axial force
            onto the first stamp portion 62, wherein the first stamp portion 62 is moved upward by means of the first
            spring 68, removing the alignment feature 78 from the burr hole plate 10. The rotation of the second stamp
            portion 64 also rotates the stamp protrusions 84 relative to the spikes 14 in such a way that the stamp
            protrusions 84 do no longer engage the spikes 14. Therefore, the surgeon can remove the deformation
            instrument 60 from the burr hole plate 10.</p>
        <p id="p0074" num="0074">Once the deformation instrument 60 has been removed from the burr hole plate 10, the
            surgeon moves the handle 74 back into the vertically elongated portion of the handle opening 76 allowing the
            second spring 72 to axially decompress. The deformation instrument 60 is now back in the initial
            configuration and can be used for the deformation of another burr hole plate 10.</p>
        <p id="p0075" num="0075">As has become apparent from the above, the burr hole plate 10 can easily be implanted
            without the need to use additional fixation elements such as bone screws, although it might be contemplated
            to pre-fix the burr hole plate 10 as explained above and additionally use one or more screws for a final
            fixation of the burr hole plate 10. In such a case the burr hole plate may additionally comprise one or more
            screw holes, for example in the region of the circumferential ring 16.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0076" num="0076">The features described in relation to the exemplary embodiments shown in the drawings
            can be readily combined to result in different embodiments. It is apparent, therefore, that the present
            disclosure may be varied in many ways. Such variations are not to be regarded as a departure from the scope
            of the invention as defined by the claims appended hereto.</p>
    </description>
    <claims id="claims01" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
        <claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
            <claim-text>A cranial plate (10), comprising:
                <claim-text>a plate body (12); and</claim-text>
                <claim-text>a plurality of spikes (14) extending from the plate body (12), the spikes (14) configured to
                    engage cranial bone, wherein the plate (10) is deformable to enable movement of the spikes (14) from
                    a disengaging configuration to an engaging configuration upon deformation of the plate (10).
                </claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 1, wherein the plate body (12) has a covering portion
                and wherein the plate (10) is deformable by applying a force onto the covering portion.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 1 or 2, wherein at last a portion of the plate body
                (12) is configured to assume one of a convex form with a positive curvature, a flat form with zero
                curvature and a concave form with a negative curvature when the spikes (14) are in a disengaging
                configuration; and<br />
                wherein the plate body (12) is deformable so that the plate body (12) assumes a form with a decreased
                curvature when the spikes (14) are in an engaging configuration.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12) is
                essentially plastically deformable.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 3, wherein the plate body (12) is
                essentially elastically deformable.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 5, wherein the plate body (12) has a bistable
                configuration and is configured to bias the spikes (14) into the engaging configuration when elastically
                deformed.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the
                spikes (14) is configured to contact a wall (34) of a burr hole when the plurality of spikes (14) is in
                the engaging configuration.
                <!-- EPO <DP n="17"> -->
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises a hub (22) and spokes (20), wherein the spokes (20) extend from the hub (22).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises a circumferential ring (16), wherein the circumferential ring (16) is configured to contact a
                cranial bone surface; wherein, as an option, the circumferential ring (16) is configured to support at
                least a subset of the plurality of spikes (14).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises an alignment feature (24) to align the plate body (12) with a deformation instrument (40; 60).
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 10, wherein the alignment feature (24) comprises at
                least one opening (26) in the plate body (12) for insertion of a portion of the deformation instrument
                (40; 60).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
            <claim-text>A deformation instrument (40; 60) for moving the spikes (14) of a cranial plate (10) according
                to any of the claims 1 to 11 into the engaging configuration, the instrument (40; 60) comprising<br />
                a radially outer sleeve (42; 66); and<br />
                a radially inner stamp (44; 62, 64) disposed inside the radially outer sleeve (42) and axially movable
                thereto, wherein the stamp (44; 62, 64) is configured to deform the plate (10) upon application of an
                axial force on the stamp (44; 62, 64).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
            <claim-text>The deformation instrument (40; 60) according to claim 12, wherein the stamp (62, 64) comprises
                a first stamp portion (62) and a second stamp portion (64), wherein the first stamp portion (62) is
                concentric to the second stamp portion (64), and wherein the first stamp portion (62) is configured to
                deform the plate body (12) of the plate (10) and the second stamp portion (64) is configured to deform
                the spikes (14) of the plate (10).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
            <claim-text>The deformation instrument (40; 60) according to claim 12 or 13, further comprising an alignment
                feature (54; 78) configured to engage the complementary alignment feature (24) of the plate body (12)
                according to claim 10.
                <!-- EPO <DP n="18"> -->
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
            <claim-text>A cranial plating system comprising<br />
                the cranial plate (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 11; and<br />
                the deformation instrument (40; 60) according to any of the claims 12 to 14.</claim-text>
        </claim>
    </claims>
    <amended-claims id="aclaims" lang="en" amend-claim-type="EPC">
        <heading id="h0006">Amended claims in accordance with Rule 137(2) EPC.</heading>
        <claim id="ac-en-0001" num="0001">
            <claim-text>A cranial plate (10), comprising:
                <claim-text>a plate body (12), wherein at least a portion of the plate body (12) is configured to assume
                    one of a convex form with a positive curvature, a flat form with zero curvature and a concave form
                    with a negative curvature when the spikes (14) are in a disengaging configuration; and</claim-text>
                <claim-text>a plurality of spikes (14) extending from the plate body (12), the spikes (14) configured to
                    engage cranial bone, wherein the plate (10) is deformable to enable movement of the spikes (14) from
                    the disengaging configuration to an engaging configuration upon deformation of the plate (10),
                    wherein the plate body (12) is deformable so that the plate body (12) assumes a form with a
                    decreased curvature when the spikes (14) are in the engaging configuration.</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0002" num="0002">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 1, wherein the plate body (12) has a covering portion
                and wherein the plate (10) is deformable by applying a force onto the covering portion.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0003" num="0003">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12) is
                essentially plastically deformable.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0004" num="0004">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 2, wherein<br />
                the plate body (12) is essentially elastically deformable.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0005" num="0005">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 4, wherein the plate body (12) has a bistable
                configuration with two stable states and is configured to bias the spikes (14) into the engaging
                configuration when elastically deformed.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0006" num="0006">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein at least one of the
                spikes (14) is configured to contact a wall (34) of a burr hole when the plurality of spikes (14) is in
                the engaging configuration.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0007" num="0007">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises a hub (22) and spokes (20), wherein the spokes (20) extend from the hub (22).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0008" num="0008">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises a circumferential ring (16), wherein the circumferential ring (16) is configured to contact a
                cranial bone surface; wherein, as an option, the circumferential ring (16) is configured to support at
                least a subset of the plurality of spikes (14).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0009" num="0009">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to any of the preceding claims, wherein the plate body (12)
                comprises an alignment feature (24) to align the plate body (12) with a deformation instrument (40; 60).
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0010" num="0010">
            <claim-text>The cranial plate (10) according to claim 9, wherein the alignment feature (24) comprises at
                least one opening (26) in the plate body (12) for insertion of a portion of the deformation instrument
                (40; 60).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0011" num="0011">
            <claim-text>A cranial plating system comprising<br />
                a cranial plate (10) according to any of the claims 1-10;<br />
                a deformation instrument (40; 60) for moving the spikes (14) of the cranial plate (10) into the engaging
                configuration, the instrument (40; 60) comprising
                <claim-text>a radially outer sleeve (42; 66); and</claim-text>
                <claim-text>a radially inner stamp (44; 62, 64) disposed inside the radially outer sleeve (42) and
                    axially movable thereto, wherein the stamp (44; 62, 64) is configured to deform the plate (10) upon
                    application of an axial force on the stamp (44; 62, 64).</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0012" num="0012">
            <claim-text>The cranial plating system according to claim 11, wherein the stamp (62, 64) comprises a first
                stamp portion (62) and a second stamp portion (64), wherein the first stamp portion (62) is concentric
                to the second stamp portion (64), and wherein the first stamp portion (62) is configured to deform the
                plate body (12) of the plate (10) and the second stamp portion (64) is configured to deform the spikes
                (14) of the plate (10).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="ac-en-0013" num="0013">
            <claim-text>The cranial plating system according to claim 11 or 12, further comprising an alignment feature
                (54; 78) configured to engage the complementary alignment feature (24) of the plate body (12) according
                to claim 9.</claim-text>
        </claim>
    </amended-claims>
    <drawings id="draw" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
        <figure id="f0001" num="1A,1B"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="141" he="230" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="20"> -->
        <figure id="f0002" num="2"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="125" he="222" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="21"> -->
        <figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="128" he="222" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
        <figure id="f0004" num="4A,4B"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="153" he="233" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
        <figure id="f0005" num="5A,5B"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="160" he="209" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="24"> -->
        <figure id="f0006" num="6A,6B"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="165" he="210" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="25"> -->
        <figure id="f0007" num="6C"><img id="if0007" file="imgf0007.tif" wi="155" he="209" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure>
    </drawings>
    <search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced="">
        <doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif" />
        <doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif" />
        <doc-page id="srep0003" file="srep0003.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif" />
        <doc-page id="srep0004" file="srep0004.tif" wi="150" he="233" type="tif" />
        <doc-page id="srep0005" file="srep0005.tif" wi="150" he="233" type="tif" />
    </search-report-data>
    <search-report-data date-produced="20171020" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n">
        <!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

        <srep-info>
            <file-reference-id>EPA-138 568</file-reference-id>
            <application-reference>
                <document-id>
                    <country>EP</country>
                    <doc-number>17001379.1</doc-number>
                </document-id>
            </application-reference>
            <applicant-name>
                <name>Stryker European Holdings I, LLC</name>
            </applicant-name>
            <srep-established srep-established="yes" />
            <srep-unity-of-invention>
                <p id="pu0001" num="">1. claims: 1-7, 9-12, 14, 15<br />The cranial plate of claim 5, wherein the plate
                    body has a bistable configuration (claim 6), for solving the problem of more easily and securely
                    implanting the cranial plate to effectively close the burr hole.</p>
                <p id="pu0002" num="">2. claim: 8<br />The cranial plate of claim 1, wherein the plate body comprises a
                    hub and spokes extending from the hub, thereby solving the problem of providing a light and stable
                    cranial plate allowing (e.g., visual) access to underlying cranial tissue and to the spikes.</p>
                <p id="pu0003" num="">3. claim: 13<br />The deformation instrument of claim 12, wherein the stamp
                    comprises a first stamp portion configured to deform the plate body and a second stamp portion
                    configured to deform the spikes, for solving the problem of providing an insertion instrument
                    capable of more effectively implanting a deformable cranial plate.</p>
                <srep-search-fees>
                    <srep-fee-4>
                        <claim-num>1-7, 9-12, 14, 15</claim-num>
                    </srep-fee-4>
                </srep-search-fees>
            </srep-unity-of-invention>
            <srep-invention-title title-approval="yes" />
            <srep-abstract abs-approval="yes" />
            <srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant">
                <figure-to-publish>
                    <fig-number>1A</fig-number>
                </figure-to-publish>
            </srep-figure-to-publish>
            <srep-info-admin>
                <srep-office>
                    <addressbook><text>DH</text></addressbook>
                </srep-office>
                <date-search-report-mailed>
                    <date>20180213</date>
                </date-search-report-mailed>
            </srep-info-admin>
        </srep-info>
        <srep-for-pub>
            <srep-fields-searched>
                <minimum-documentation>
                    <classifications-ipcr>
                        <classification-ipcr><text>A61B</text></classification-ipcr>
                    </classifications-ipcr>
                </minimum-documentation>
            </srep-fields-searched>
            <srep-citations>
                <citation id="sr-cit0001">
                    <patcit dnum="WO2011005788A1" id="sr-pcit0001"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=WO2011005788&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>2011005788</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <name>SYNTHES USA LLC [US]; SYNTHES GMBH [CH]; STEPHAN KAI [CH]; GRIFFITHS B</name>
                            <date>20110113</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>X</category>
                    <rel-claims>1-5,7,9-12,14,15</rel-claims>
                    <category>A</category>
                    <rel-claims>6</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* paragraphs [0210], [0211]; figures 21A, 21B *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
                <citation id="sr-cit0002">
                    <patcit dnum="EP1808140A1" id="sr-pcit0002"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=EP1808140&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1808140</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <name>BIODYNAMICS LLC [US]</name>
                            <date>20070718</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>X</category>
                    <rel-claims>1</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* figure 18B *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
                <citation id="sr-cit0003">
                    <patcit dnum="US5800436A" id="sr-pcit0003"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US5800436&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5800436</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <name>LERCH KARL-DIETER [DE]</name>
                            <date>19980901</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>X</category>
                    <rel-claims>1</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* figure 4 *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
                <citation id="sr-cit0004">
                    <patcit dnum="US6923812B1" id="sr-pcit0004"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US6923812&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>6923812</doc-number>
                            <kind>B1</kind>
                            <name>WELLISZ TADEUSZ Z [US]</name>
                            <date>20050802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>X</category>
                    <rel-claims>1</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* figure 4 *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
            </srep-citations>
            <srep-admin>
                <examiners>
                    <primary-examiner>
                        <name>Fernández Arillo, J</name>
                    </primary-examiner>
                </examiners>
                <srep-office>
                    <addressbook><text>The Hague</text></addressbook>
                </srep-office>
                <date-search-completed>
                    <date>20171020</date>
                </date-search-completed>
            </srep-admin>
            <!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						-->
            <srep-patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>2011005788</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20110113</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>BR</country>
                            <doc-number>PI1014714</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>20170718</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CA</country>
                            <doc-number>2767403</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20110113</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CN</country>
                            <doc-number>102470007</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20120523</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CN</country>
                            <doc-number>105342683</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20160224</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>2451373</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20120516</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>5907458</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>20160426</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>6193416</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>20170906</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>2012532006</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20121213</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>2016083575</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20160519</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>KR</country>
                            <doc-number>20120052265</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20120523</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2011046682</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20110224</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2015150612</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20150604</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>2011005788</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20110113</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                </patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1808140</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070718</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AU</country>
                            <doc-number>2006336404</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AU</country>
                            <doc-number>2010241287</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20101125</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CA</country>
                            <doc-number>2636213</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CN</country>
                            <doc-number>101360461</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20090204</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1808140</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070718</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1897508</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>20080312</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>2250969</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>20101117</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>ES</country>
                            <doc-number>2395295</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20130211</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>2009523534</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20090625</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>KR</country>
                            <doc-number>20080098611</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20081111</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>NZ</country>
                            <doc-number>569216</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20110729</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2007173844</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070726</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2010179553</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20100715</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2010179554</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20100715</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2011054540</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20110303</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2012136397</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20120531</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>2007086901</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20070802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                </patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5800436</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19980901</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>DE</country>
                            <doc-number>19603887</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19970814</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>0787466</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19970806</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>0920837</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>19990609</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>ES</country>
                            <doc-number>2140156</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20000216</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>ES</country>
                            <doc-number>2217627</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20041101</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>3011896</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>20000221</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>H09206311</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19970812</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5800436</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19980901</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>6068631</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20000530</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>6270500</doc-number>
                            <kind>B1</kind>
                            <date>20010807</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2001011173</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20010802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2002040224</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20020404</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2004172029</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20040902</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2006009772</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20060112</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                </patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>6923812</doc-number>
                            <kind>B1</kind>
                            <date>20050802</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application><text>NONE</text>
                </patent-family>
            </srep-patent-family>
        </srep-for-pub>
    </search-report-data>
</ep-patent-document>