<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ep-patent-document PUBLIC "-//EPO//EP PATENT DOCUMENT 1.5//EN" "ep-patent-document-v1-5.dtd">
<ep-patent-document id="EP17185386A1" file="EP17185386NWA1.xml" lang="en" country="EP" doc-number="3441143" kind="A1"
    date-publ="20190213" status="n" dtd-version="ep-patent-document-v1-5">
    <SDOBI lang="en">
        <B000>
            <eptags>
                <B001EP>
                    ATBECHDEDKESFRGBGRITLILUNLSEMCPTIESILTLVFIROMKCYALTRBGCZEEHUPLSKBAHRIS..MTNORSMESMMA....MD..........
                </B001EP>
                <B005EP>J</B005EP>
                <B007EP>BDM Ver 0.1.63 (23 May 2017) - 1100000/0</B007EP>
            </eptags>
        </B000>
        <B100>
            <B110>3441143</B110>
            <B120>
                <B121>EUROPEAN PATENT APPLICATION</B121>
            </B120>
            <B130>A1</B130>
            <B140>
                <date>20190213</date>
            </B140>
            <B190>EP</B190>
        </B100>
        <B200>
            <B210>17185386.4</B210>
            <B220>
                <date>20170808</date>
            </B220>
            <B250>en</B250>
            <B251EP>en</B251EP>
            <B260>en</B260>
        </B200>
        <B400>
            <B405>
                <date>20190213</date>
                <bnum>201907</bnum>
            </B405>
            <B430>
                <date>20190213</date>
                <bnum>201907</bnum>
            </B430>
        </B400>
        <B500>
            <B510EP>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="1"><text>B01L 9/00 20060101AFI20180122BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="2"><text>B01L 9/06 20060101ALI20180122BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="3"><text>G01N 35/10 20060101ALI20180122BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
                <classification-ipcr sequence="4"><text>G01N 35/04 20060101ALI20180122BHEP </text></classification-ipcr>
            </B510EP>
            <B540>
                <B541>de</B541>
                <B542>LABORINSTRUMENTGRUNDPLATTE</B542>
                <B541>en</B541>
                <B542>LABORATORY INSTRUMENT BASE PLATE</B542>
                <B541>fr</B541>
                <B542>PLAQUE DE BASE D'INSTRUMENT DE LABORATOIRE</B542>
            </B540>
            <B590>
                <B598>1</B598>
            </B590>
        </B500>
        <B700>
            <B710>
                <B711>
                    <snm>Roche Diagnostics GmbH</snm>
                    <iid>101456586</iid>
                    <irf>P34267-EP-TB</irf>
                    <adr>
                        <str>Sandhofer Straße 116</str>
                        <city>68305 Mannheim</city>
                        <ctry>DE</ctry>
                    </adr>
                    <B716EP>
                        <ctry>DE</ctry>
                    </B716EP>
                </B711>
                <B711>
                    <snm>F. Hoffmann-La Roche AG</snm>
                    <iid>101649847</iid>
                    <irf>P34267-EP-TB</irf>
                    <adr>
                        <str>Grenzacherstrasse 124</str>
                        <city>4070 Basel</city>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                    </adr>
                    <B716EP>
                        <ctry>AL</ctry>
                        <ctry>AT</ctry>
                        <ctry>BE</ctry>
                        <ctry>BG</ctry>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                        <ctry>CY</ctry>
                        <ctry>CZ</ctry>
                        <ctry>DK</ctry>
                        <ctry>EE</ctry>
                        <ctry>ES</ctry>
                        <ctry>FI</ctry>
                        <ctry>FR</ctry>
                        <ctry>GB</ctry>
                        <ctry>GR</ctry>
                        <ctry>HR</ctry>
                        <ctry>HU</ctry>
                        <ctry>IE</ctry>
                        <ctry>IS</ctry>
                        <ctry>IT</ctry>
                        <ctry>LI</ctry>
                        <ctry>LT</ctry>
                        <ctry>LU</ctry>
                        <ctry>LV</ctry>
                        <ctry>MC</ctry>
                        <ctry>MK</ctry>
                        <ctry>MT</ctry>
                        <ctry>NL</ctry>
                        <ctry>NO</ctry>
                        <ctry>PL</ctry>
                        <ctry>PT</ctry>
                        <ctry>RO</ctry>
                        <ctry>RS</ctry>
                        <ctry>SE</ctry>
                        <ctry>SI</ctry>
                        <ctry>SK</ctry>
                        <ctry>SM</ctry>
                        <ctry>TR</ctry>
                    </B716EP>
                </B711>
            </B710>
            <B720>
                <B721>
                    <snm>BERNET Roland</snm>
                    <adr>
                        <str>c/o Roche Diagnostics International AG,
                            Forrenstrasse2</str>
                        <city>CH-6343 Rotkreuz</city>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B721>
                <B721>
                    <snm>SANGERMANO, Marco</snm>
                    <adr>
                        <str>c/o Roche Diagnostics International AG,
                            Forrenstrasse2</str>
                        <city>CH-6343 Rotkreuz</city>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B721>
                <B721>
                    <snm>SIEGENTHALER Simon</snm>
                    <adr>
                        <str>c/o Brandenberger proe GmbH,
                            In der Fadmatt 56</str>
                        <city>CH-8902 Urdorf</city>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B721>
            </B720>
            <B740>
                <B741>
                    <snm>Herren, Barbara</snm>
                    <iid>101338862</iid>
                    <adr>
                        <str>Roche Diagnostics International AG
                            Forrenstrasse 2</str>
                        <city>6343 Rotkreuz</city>
                        <ctry>CH</ctry>
                    </adr>
                </B741>
            </B740>
        </B700>
        <B800>
            <B840>
                <ctry>AL</ctry>
                <ctry>AT</ctry>
                <ctry>BE</ctry>
                <ctry>BG</ctry>
                <ctry>CH</ctry>
                <ctry>CY</ctry>
                <ctry>CZ</ctry>
                <ctry>DE</ctry>
                <ctry>DK</ctry>
                <ctry>EE</ctry>
                <ctry>ES</ctry>
                <ctry>FI</ctry>
                <ctry>FR</ctry>
                <ctry>GB</ctry>
                <ctry>GR</ctry>
                <ctry>HR</ctry>
                <ctry>HU</ctry>
                <ctry>IE</ctry>
                <ctry>IS</ctry>
                <ctry>IT</ctry>
                <ctry>LI</ctry>
                <ctry>LT</ctry>
                <ctry>LU</ctry>
                <ctry>LV</ctry>
                <ctry>MC</ctry>
                <ctry>MK</ctry>
                <ctry>MT</ctry>
                <ctry>NL</ctry>
                <ctry>NO</ctry>
                <ctry>PL</ctry>
                <ctry>PT</ctry>
                <ctry>RO</ctry>
                <ctry>RS</ctry>
                <ctry>SE</ctry>
                <ctry>SI</ctry>
                <ctry>SK</ctry>
                <ctry>SM</ctry>
                <ctry>TR</ctry>
            </B840>
            <B844EP>
                <B845EP>
                    <ctry>BA</ctry>
                </B845EP>
                <B845EP>
                    <ctry>ME</ctry>
                </B845EP>
            </B844EP>
            <B848EP>
                <B849EP>
                    <ctry>MA</ctry>
                </B849EP>
                <B849EP>
                    <ctry>MD</ctry>
                </B849EP>
            </B848EP>
        </B800>
    </SDOBI>
    <abstract id="abst" lang="en">
        <p id="pa01" num="0001">A laboratory instrument comprising a single base plate is presented. The single base
            plate comprises at least one embedded consumable compartment, an embedded sample processing compartment, an
            embedded waste compartment, an embedded activation device compartment, an embedded rack receiving
            compartment, or a combination thereof. A laboratory system and a method adjusting the positioning of at
            least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory instrument or laboratory system are also
            disclosed.
            <img id="iaf01" file="imgaf001.tif" wi="72" he="101" img-content="drawing" img-format="tif" /></p>
    </abstract>
    <description id="desc" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="1"> -->
        <heading id="h0001"><b><u>Field of the Invention</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0001" num="0001">The present invention belongs to the field of automated in vitro diagnostic sample
            processing. Within this field, it relates to a laboratory instrument, a laboratory system and a method for
            adjusting the positioning of pipetting devices or handling devices of laboratory instruments or laboratory
            systems in order to ensure accuracy and safety of certain sample processing steps.</p>
        <heading id="h0002"><b><u>Background</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0002" num="0002">In diagnostic laboratories, automated pre-analytical, analytical, and post-analytical
            laboratory instruments are used for various sample processing steps to produce accurate and reliable test
            results which represent pivotal information for physicians. Typically, such laboratory instruments are
            equipped with consumables, sample processing devices, waste containers, sample racks, and reagent racks
            which are accommodated in dedicated units assembled on a working surface within the laboratory instrument.
            Thus, the interior and the working surface of a laboratory instrument are built with a plurality of units
            and construction components which must be precisely adapted to one another for being assembled.</p>
        <p id="p0003" num="0003">For a reliable and safe operation, such laboratory instruments have to be well
            maintained. The different components and the working surface of the laboratory instrument have to be cleaned
            on a regular basis to avoid cross contaminations which can lead to erroneous test results. The thorough
            cleaning of the interior of the laboratory instrument also ensures the safety of the operator and extends
            the laboratory instrument lifetime. As the downtime of the laboratory instrument should be kept as short as
            possible, the cleaning of the laboratory instrument should be as efficient as possible. However, as
            conventional laboratory instruments comprise multiple assembled units and construction components, the
            working surface of the laboratory instrument may possess small gaps and splits which complicate the thorough
            cleaning of the interior of the laboratory instrument. Particularly, in laboratory instruments in the area
            of nucleic acid analytics
            <!-- EPO <DP n="2"> --> where a highly sensitive analytical technology is used, smallest impurities may have
            severe consequences on test results and subsequent diagnosis.</p>
        <p id="p0004" num="0004">Some sample processing steps include pipetting operations like the aspiration and/or
            dispensation of liquid samples and reagents out of and/or into vessels using a pipetting device. For those
            pipetting operations an accurate positioning of the pipette device relative to the sample vessels or reagent
            vessels positioned on the working surface is important as a physical contact between the pipette tip of the
            pipetting device and the sample vessels or reagent vessels can cause sample cross-contamination, reagent
            cross-contamination, and/ or damage of the vessels or pipetting device of the laboratory instrument.
            Therefore, the positioning of the pipetting device has to be adjusted or calibrated on a regular basis.</p>
        <p id="p0005" num="0005">
            <patcit id="pcit0001" dnum="US20140263879A1"><text>US 2014/0263879 A1</text></patcit> and <patcit
                id="pcit0002" dnum="US20090090198A1"><text>US 2009/0090198 A1</text></patcit> disclose laboratory
            apparatuses providing base plates or working surfaces for mounting or positioning other elements of the
            apparatuses.
        </p>
        <p id="p0006" num="0006">There is a need to maintain diagnostic laboratory instruments in a simple and efficient
            way. It was an object of the present invention to improve conventional instrument working surfaces,
            particularly to better serve the needs of automated in vitro diagnostic sample processing.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="3"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0003"><b><u>Summary</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0007" num="0007">The present invention discloses a laboratory instrument, a laboratory system and a
            method for adjusting the positioning of at least one pipetting device or handling device of the laboratory
            instrument or laboratory system.</p>
        <p id="p0008" num="0008">The laboratory instrument comprises a single base plate comprising at least one
            embedded compartment. At least one of said embedded compartment is selected from a group consisting of an
            embedded consumable compartment, an embedded sample processing compartment, an embedded waste compartment,
            an embedded activation device compartment, an embedded rack receiving compartment, or a combination thereof.
        </p>
        <p id="p0009" num="0009">The present invention also relates to a laboratory system which comprises a laboratory
            instrument as described herein and at least one consumable or at least one sample processing device or at
            least one rack or a combination thereof.</p>
        <p id="p0010" num="0010">The present invention also relates to a method for adjusting the positioning of at
            least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory instrument or laboratory system as described
            herein. The method comprises the following steps:
            <ul id="ul0001" list-style="bullet" compact="compact">
                <li>the at least one transfer system moves the at least one pipetting device or handling device towards
                    the at least one reference structure</li>
                <li>the at least one reference structure detection device of the at least one pipetting device or
                    handling device detects the at least one reference structure, wherein the at least one reference
                    structure detection device generates at least one signal upon detection of the at least one
                    reference structure and sends the at least one signal to the control device</li>
                <li>the control device receives the at least one signal from the at least one reference structure
                    detection device and determines position information of the at least one reference structure based
                    on the received at least one signal</li>
                <li>the control device compares the determined position information of the at least one reference
                    structure with predefined position information of the at least one reference structure</li>
                <li>the control device determines and stores a deviation between the determined position information of
                    the at least one reference structure and the predefined position information of the at least one
                    reference structure
                    <!-- EPO <DP n="4"> -->
                </li>
                <li>the control device adjusts the positioning of the at least one pipetting device or handling device
                    of the laboratory instrument or laboratory system according to the determined and stored deviation
                    between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure and the
                    predefined position information of the at least one reference structure.</li>
            </ul><!-- EPO <DP n="5"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0004"><b><u>Detailed description</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0011" num="0011">The present invention relates to a laboratory instrument which comprises a single base
            plate comprising at least one embedded compartment. At least one of said embedded compartment is selected
            from a group consisting of an embedded consumable compartment, an embedded sample processing compartment, an
            embedded waste compartment, an embedded activation device compartment, an embedded rack receiving
            compartment, or a combination thereof.</p>
        <p id="p0012" num="0012">As used herein, the term "laboratory instrument" relates to any pre-analytical,
            analytical, or post-analytical instrument for performing sample or sample vessel processing steps. A
            pre-analytical instrument can usually be used for the preliminary processing of samples or sample vessels.
            An analytical instrument can be designed, for example, to use a sample or part of the sample and a reagent
            in order to produce a measurable signal, on the basis of which it is possible to determine whether the
            analyte is present, and if desired in what concentration. A post-analytical instrument can usually be used
            for the post-processing of samples like the archiving of samples. The pre-analytical, analytical and
            post-analytical instrument may comprise, for example, at least one device from the group of following
            devices: a sorting device for sorting samples or sample vessels, a cap removal device for removing caps or
            closures on sample vessels, a cap fitting device for fitting caps or closures on sample vessels, a pipetting
            device for pipetting a sample, an aliquoting device for aliquoting samples, a centrifuging device for
            centrifuging samples, an analyzing device for analyzing a sample, a heating device for heating a sample, a
            cooling device for cooling a sample, a mixing device for mixing a sample, a separation device for isolating
            an analyte of the sample, a storing device for storing samples, an archiving device for archiving samples, a
            sample vessel type determination device for determining a sample vessel type, a sample quality determination
            device for determining a sample quality. The laboratory instrument may comprise a three-dimensional
            rectangular coordinate system comprising a x direction, y direction, and z direction which are
            perpendicularly aligned with respect to each other, with the first and second directions (x, y) spanning a
            plane and the third direction (z) being perpendicularly aligned with respect to the plane. In one
            embodiment, the first and second directions (x, y) can span a horizontal plane and the third direction (z)
            can be vertically aligned (direction of fall). In the following description, reference is made to the three
            directions x, y, and z.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="6"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0013" num="0013">As used herein, the term "single base plate" relates to a plate mounted within the
            laboratory instrument which represents the actual working surface on which sample, sample vessel, reagent
            and/ or reagent vessel processing steps of the laboratory instrument are carried out. For this purpose, the
            base plate is provided with embedded compartments for accommodating consumables, sample processing devices,
            waste containers, activation devices, and racks which are required for carrying out the sample, sample
            vessel, reagent and/ or reagent vessel processing steps. The single base plate consists of one single piece
            and can be made of any suitable material with sufficient rigidity (e.g. metal and/ or plastic). The single
            base plate may have different shapes and forms to meet the requirements of the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0014" num="0014">The term "embedded compartment" as used herein, means that the compartment and the
            single base plate consist of one single formed piece. Thus, there are no gaps or splits between the actual
            working surface and the embedded compartment which allows an efficient and thorough cleaning of the working
            surface of the laboratory instrument. The embedded compartment encompasses an inner volume and may be
            designed as recesses or protrusions of the single base plate.</p>
        <p id="p0015" num="0015">As used herein, the term "embedded consumable compartment" relates to a dedicated
            embedded compartment of the single base plate adapted for receiving, storing, and/ or releasing consumables
            used for operating a laboratory instrument. The embedded consumable compartment can be manually or
            automatically loaded/ unloaded with consumables like for example pipette tip racks, sample vessel racks,
            multiwell plates, reagent containers, reagent container racks, or reaction vessel racks.</p>
        <p id="p0016" num="0016">As used herein, the term "embedded sample processing compartment" relates to a
            dedicated embedded compartment of the single base plate adapted for mounting or accommodating one or more
            sample processing devices used for conducting sample processing steps. Examples of sample processing devices
            are heating devices, cooling devices, mixing devices, separation devices, analyzing devices, storing
            devices, or centrifugation devices.</p>
        <p id="p0017" num="0017">As used herein, the term "embedded waste compartment" relates to a dedicated embedded
            compartment of the single base plate adapted for receiving, storing, and/or releasing waste containers. The
            embedded waste compartment can be manually or automatically loaded/
            <!-- EPO <DP n="7"> --> unloaded with waste containers like for example tip waste racks or waste bags used
            for disposing used consumables, samples or reagents.</p>
        <p id="p0018" num="0018">As used herein, the term "embedded activation device compartment" relates to a
            dedicated embedded compartment of the single base plate for accommodating an activation device. The term
            "activation device" as used herein relates to a stationary structure which can engage with a part of a
            moving device like a pipetting device or handling device. And the activation device can activate or change a
            specific mechanism or functionality of the moving device by means of engagement with the part of the moving
            device. An activation device may be designed as described in <patcit id="pcit0003" dnum="WO2017064089A">
                <text>WO2017/064089</text></patcit>, reference number 176 in figures 11, 12, 13, 14, 16 and
            corresponding figure descriptions.</p>
        <p id="p0019" num="0019">As used herein, the term "embedded rack receiving compartment" relates to an embedded
            compartment of the single base plate adapted for loading and unloading racks. The embedded rack receiving
            compartment can be manually or automatically loaded/ unloaded with racks like for example sample vessel
            racks or reagent container racks.</p>
        <p id="p0020" num="0020">In one embodiment of the laboratory instrument as described herein, the laboratory
            instrument comprises a housing. The housing comprises a frame and the single base plate is mounted on the
            frame within the laboratory instrument. As the housing comprises a frame configured to support the base
            plate, the housing serves also as a supporting structure. The housing may further comprise a bottom plate, a
            rear wall, two opposing side walls, a front wall, and a top wall. Thus, the interior of the laboratory
            instrument may be protected from the environment by the housing. Thereby, pollution from outside or unwanted
            access to the interior of the laboratory instrument is prevented. The front wall and/or top wall may form a
            hood which can be moved from a closed position, in which an interior of the housing is prevented from
            access, to an open position, in which the interior of the housing is exposed so as to allow access, and vice
            versa. The frame may comprise a plurality of profiles. The profiles are connected to one another. Thus, the
            frame may be designed in a modular manner as it is built up by profiles. Particularly, the use of profiles
            allows for a variety of designs and a scaled up or scaled down construction of the frame. The term "profile"
            as used herein refers to an elongated constructional member. The profiles may be made by extrusion. As such,
            the profiles may be so called extrusion profiles. The profiles may be connected to one another using
            connecting elements such
            <!-- EPO <DP n="8"> --> as screws or clamps. The profiles may be made of plastics and/or metal. For example,
            the profiles are made of aluminium for a lightweight construction. As the single base plate is mounted on
            the frame, the single base plate contributes to the stability of the housing.</p>
        <p id="p0021" num="0021">In an alternative embodiment, the laboratory instrument comprises a scaffold or
            supporting structure enclosed by a laboratory instrument case which covers the interior of the laboratory
            instrument to protect it from the environment. And the single base plate is mounted on the scaffold or
            supporting structure within the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0022" num="0022">In one embodiment of the single base plate, the single base plate is made of
            thermoplastic or duroplastic polymers which are well known in the art. By supplying energy, those polymers
            can be brought into a desired shape or form of the single base plate by various manufacturing or forming
            processes. After the single base plate has cooled, it retains its shape and form. For example, the single
            base plate is made of the thermoplastic polymer ABS GF 17 (Acrylonitrile butadiene styrene with 17 % glass
            fibre) for a light and the same time stable construction.</p>
        <p id="p0023" num="0023">In a further embodiment of the single base plate, the single base plate is an injection
            molding plate. Injection molding is a manufacturing or forming process for producing a work piece like the
            single base plate by injecting material like thermoplastic or duroplastic polymers into a mold. Material for
            the single base plate is fed into a heated barrel, mixed, and forced into a mold cavity, where it cools and
            hardens to the configuration of the cavity. With injection molding almost all shapes or forms of the single
            base plate and the at least one embedded compartment which are formed as one single piece can be
            manufactured with high precision and at a low price. Among the various possible manufacturing or forming
            processes, the thermoplastic foam injection molding is well suited for the production of a single base plate
            with a certain size required for laboratory instruments.</p>
        <p id="p0024" num="0024">In an alternative embodiment, the single base plate is a 3D printer product. 3D
            printers can produce a virtually free-formable single base plate from a filament consisting of thermoplastic
            or duroplastic polymers. As no mold cavity is used for the forming process, 3D printing is well suited to
            produce small batches of single base plates.</p>
        <p id="p0025" num="0025">In one embodiment of the single base plate, the single base plate is coated with an UV
            light and reagent resistant varnish. As UV light is widely used for decontaminating the interior and working
            surfaces of laboratory instruments, the UV light resistant characteristics of the varnish
            <!-- EPO <DP n="9"> --> can protect the single base plate from UV light based deteriorations. During
            operation of the laboratory instrument, the single base plate may also be exposed to various reagents (test
            reagents, elution buffers, lysis buffers, washing buffers, etc.) as sample and sample vessel processing
            steps like pipetting operations or removal/ fitting of sample vessel caps can cause splashes, droplets or
            aerosol. Thus, the base plate has to be protected from reagents as well as cleaning agents in order to
            prevent damages of the single base plate. One example of a varnish with good UV light and reagent resistant
            characteristics suitable for the single base plate is Duoplast U242.</p>
        <p id="p0026" num="0026">In one embodiment of the at least one embedded compartment, the at least one embedded
            compartment comprises rounded corners or rounded edges or a combination thereof. Thereby, no impurities can
            accumulate in corners and cleaning of the single base plate is more thorough and efficient.</p>
        <p id="p0027" num="0027">In a further embodiment of the at least one embedded compartment, the at least one
            embedded compartment comprises at least two side walls which encompass an inner volume, a bottom, and an
            open top, wherein the at least two side walls are opposite each other or adjacent each other. The side walls
            and bottom of the embedded compartment may be closed surfaces or may have one or more openings for providing
            access to the inner volume from the side or from below. Access to the inner volume from the side or below
            may be advantageous for providing the electrical power supply and/ or mounting of sample processing devices
            within a sample processing compartment. Additionally, the one or more openings of the side walls and bottom
            may serve for heat dissipation.</p>
        <p id="p0028" num="0028">In one embodiment of the embedded consumable compartment, the embedded consumable
            compartment may have four closed side walls which are opposite each other, a closed bottom, and an open top
            into which at least one consumable can be inserted.</p>
        <p id="p0029" num="0029">In one embodiment of the embedded waste compartment, the embedded waste compartment may
            have four closed side walls which are opposite each other, a closed bottom, and an open top into which at
            least one waste container can be inserted.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="10"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0030" num="0030">In one embodiment of the embedded rack receiving compartment, the embedded rack
            receiving compartment may have three side walls and a closed bottom forming a rack slot with a closed rear
            end and an open front end into which one or multiple sample vessel racks or reagent container racks can be
            inserted.</p>
        <p id="p0031" num="0031">In one embodiment of the embedded sample processing device compartment, the embedded
            sample processing device compartment may have four side walls, a bottom with at least one opening, an open
            top into which at least one sample processing device can be mounted.</p>
        <p id="p0032" num="0032">In one embodiment of the single base plate, the single base plate further comprises at
            least one embedded support element. At least one of said embedded support element is selected from a group
            consisting of a cable channel, an air channel, a display frame, an identification device or sensor holder,
            an instrument interlock module, a latch-fit or snap-latch, or a combination thereof. The term "embedded
            support element" as used herein, means that the support element and the single base plate consist of one
            single formed piece. Accordingly, the number of construction components is further reduced compared to
            conventional constructions of laboratory instruments.</p>
        <p id="p0033" num="0033">In a further embodiment of the single base plate, the single base plate comprises at
            least one reference structure. The at least one reference structure comprises a geometric form for
            determining reference position information within the three-dimensional rectangular coordinate system of the
            laboratory instrument. The at least one reference structure can be a defined reference bolt or reference
            mark which is designed as a rectangular recesses, round recesses, cubic protrusion or cylindrical protrusion
            of the single base plate. The at least one reference structure of the single base plate is detectable by a
            reference structure detection device like a pressure sensor, an air pressure sensor, an optical sensor, a
            laser, an ultrasound sensor, or a combination thereof. Upon detection of the reference structure of the
            single base plate, reference position information within the interior of the laboratory instrument or
            laboratory system is determined and used for adjusting or calibrating the positioning of at the least one
            pipetting device or handling device of the laboratory instrument or laboratory system.</p>
        <p id="p0034" num="0034">In one embodiment of the laboratory instrument, the laboratory instrument additionally
            comprises at least one electrically conductive element. The at least one electrically conductive element is
            mounted on the single base plate. The electrically conductive element can be made of
            <!-- EPO <DP n="11"> --> any conductive material and can have any geometric form and size. The term
            "electrically conductive" as used herein, means that the material of which the element is made of has the
            property to conduct an electrical current.</p>
        <p id="p0035" num="0035">In one embodiment of the at least one electrically conductive element, the at least one
            electrically conductive element comprises at least one reference structure. The at least one reference
            structure comprises a geometric form for determining reference position information within the
            three-dimensional rectangular coordinate system of the laboratory instrument. The at least one reference
            structure can be a defined reference bolt or reference mark which is designed as a rectangular recesses,
            round recesses, cubic protrusion or cylindrical protrusion of the electrically conductive element.</p>
        <p id="p0036" num="0036">In one embodiment of the at least one reference structure, the at least one reference
            structure can be defined as a through-hole of the electrically conductive element. The at least one
            reference structure of the electrically conductive element is detectable by a reference structure detection
            device like a conductive pipette tip, a conductive pipette nozzle, a conductive gripper finger, a pressure
            sensor, an air pressure sensor, an optical sensor, a laser, an ultrasound sensor, or a combination thereof.
            Upon detection of the reference structure, reference position information within the interior of the
            laboratory instrument or laboratory system is determined and used for adjusting or calibrating the
            positioning of the at least one pipetting device or handling device of the laboratory instrument or
            laboratory system as described further below.</p>
        <p id="p0037" num="0037">In a further embodiment of the at least one electrically conductive element, the at
            least one electrically conductive element comprises one or more electrically conductive sheets. At least one
            of the one or more electrically conductive sheets comprises at least one through-hole and the at least one
            through-hole is aligned with the open top of at least one embedded compartment of the single base plate. The
            form of the at least one through-hole is congruent with the open top of at least one embedded compartment so
            that consumables can be loaded/ unloaded into the embedded consumable compartment, a sample processing
            device in the embedded sample processing compartment can be accessed by the operator or pipetting/ handling
            device, a waste container can be loaded/ unloaded into the embedded waste compartment, or racks can be
            loaded/ unloaded into the embedded rack receiving compartment.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="12"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0038" num="0038">In a specific embodiment of the at least one electrically conductive element, the at
            least one electrically conductive element is made of aluminum.</p>
        <p id="p0039" num="0039">In one embodiment of the one or more electrically conductive sheets, the at least one
            through-hole is the least one reference structure. The through-hole may be rectangular and the two edges
            which are perpendicular to each other define the x and y values of the reference position information.
            Alternatively, the x and y values of the reference position information can also be defined with a round
            through-hole. The z value of the reference position information can be defined by the position of the
            electrically conductive sheet along the z direction. As the reference structure can be a through-hole which
            is aligned and congruent with the open top of an embedded consumable compartment there is enough free space
            for moving the reference structure detection device towards the edges of the through-hole without
            encountering any obstacles. This allows a safe and accurate detection of the reference structure.
            Furthermore, a space-saving design of the interior of the laboratory instrument is possible as no additional
            free space is necessary for moving the reference structure detection device towards the reference structure.
        </p>
        <p id="p0040" num="0040">In a further embodiment of the one or more electrically conductive sheets, the one or
            more electrically conductive sheets comprise at least one latch-fit or snap-latch. The latch-fit or
            snap-latch is located on the electrically conductive sheet so that consumables with corresponding counter
            snap-latches or latch-fits can be attached precisely and reversibly to the electrically conductive sheet.
            Thus, consumables can be easily loaded/ unloaded manually and at the same time the consumables like for
            example pipette tip racks are precisely and vertically aligned for an optimal operation of the laboratory
            instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0041" num="0041">In one embodiment of the one or more electrically conductive sheets, the one or more
            electrically conductive sheets are mounted on the single base plate with one or more screws. Alternatively,
            the one or more electrically conductive sheets can be mounted on the single base plate with one or more
            clamps.</p>
        <p id="p0042" num="0042">In a more specific embodiment, the one or more screws are shoulder screws, wherein the
            one or more electrically conductive sheets are additionally mounted with at least one fixed-point on the
            single base plate. To ensure that the different thermal expansions of metal (e.g. aluminum) and plastic
            (e.g. thermoplastic polymer) do not cause any tensioning of the single base plate and
            <!-- EPO <DP n="13"> --> the one or more electrically conductive sheets, the one or more electrically
            conductive sheets are mounted with shoulder screws which permit a compensation of the thermal expansion in
            the x and y directions and prevent a compensation of the thermal expansion in the z direction. In order to
            restrict the x and y directions of the thermal expansion the one or more electrically conductive sheets are
            pinned with at least one fixed-point on the single base plate. The at least one fixed point can be a square,
            round or oblong hole in the one or more electrically conductive sheets. The single base plate comprises pins
            which are vertically aligned to the fixed-points so that the pins can engage the fix-points for a floating
            mounting of the one or more electrically conductive sheets on the single base plate.</p>
        <p id="p0043" num="0043">In one embodiment of the laboratory instrument, the laboratory instrument comprises at
            least one pipetting device or handling device. The at least one pipetting device or handling device
            comprises at least one reference structure detection device. The laboratory instrument further comprises at
            least one transfer system which is connected to the at least one pipetting device or handling device. The at
            least one transfer system is constructed to move the at least one pipetting device or handling device in the
            three-dimensional directions within the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0044" num="0044">The term "pipetting device" as used herein relates to a device which either couples
            disposable pipette tips or comprises pipetting needles, and which can aspirate and dispense samples and/ or
            reagents necessary for performing sample processing steps. In one embodiment, the pipetting device has one
            pipette tip or needle for aspirating and/or dispensing one sample or reagent or a combination thereof.
            Alternatively, the pipetting device has multiple pipette tips or needles for aspirating and/or dispensing
            multiple samples or reagents or a combination thereof at the same time. The one or more pipette tip or
            needle can additionally be a reference structure detection device.</p>
        <p id="p0045" num="0045">The term "handling device" as used herein relates to a device which can grip and move
            items within the laboratory instrument. In one embodiment, the handling device comprises gripper fingers for
            gripping and moving consumables, waste containers, sample vessels, or reagent vessels in order to load/
            unload the corresponding embedded consumable compartments. Such a handling device can also be used for
            removing and/ or fitting caps or closures on sample vessels and/ or regent containers. The gripper finger or
            fingers can additionally be a reference structure detection device.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="14"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0046" num="0046">The term "transfer system" as used herein relates to a device for moving the at least
            one pipetting device or handling device within the interior of the laboratory instrument. In one embodiment,
            the transfer system comprises at least one guide rail along each of the three directions x, y, and z of the
            three-dimensional rectangular coordinate system of the laboratory instrument. The pipetting device or
            handling device is movable in the x, y, and z direction along those guide rails by suitable drives. In
            another embodiment, the transfer system comprises at least one guide rail along each x and y direction and
            the pipetting device contains a drive for moving the pipette tip in the z direction. The pipetting device is
            movable along the guide rail along the x direction. And the guide rail along the x direction is in turn
            movable on the at least one rail along the y direction by means of a suitable drive. The at least one rail
            along the y direction is mounted on the single base plate. In an alternative embodiment, the transfer system
            is an arm of an industrial robot comprising one or more movable joints for moving the pipetting device or
            handling device in the three-dimensional directions within the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0047" num="0047">The term "reference structure detection device" as used herein relates to a device
            which can detect the reference structure and sends signals to a control device for determining reference
            position information consisting of x, y, and z values based on the detected reference structure. In one
            embodiment, the at least one reference structure detection device of the at least one pipetting device is
            selected from a group consisting of a conductive pipette tip, a conductive pipette nozzle, a pressure
            sensor, an air pressure sensor, an optical sensor, a laser, an ultrasound sensor, or a combination thereof.
            In one embodiment, the reference structure detection device of the at least one handling device is selected
            from a group consisting of a conductive gripper finger, a pressure sensor, an optical sensor, a laser, an
            ultrasound sensor, or a combination thereof.</p>
        <p id="p0048" num="0048">The present invention also relates to a laboratory system which comprises a laboratory
            instrument as described herein and at least one consumable or at least one sample processing device or at
            least one rack or a combination thereof.</p>
        <p id="p0049" num="0049">The term "consumable" as used herein relates to an item used in sample processing steps
            and subsequently discarded, such as, as non-limiting examples, plastic consumables such as pipette tips,
            pipette tip racks, sample vessels, sample vessel racks, multiwell plates, reagent containers, reagent
            container racks, reaction vessels, reaction vessel racks. Such consumables are well known in the art.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="15"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0050" num="0050">The term "sample processing device" as used herein relates to a device for processing a
            sample such as, as non-limiting examples, heating devices, cooling devices, mixing devices, separation
            devices, analyzing devices, storing devices, or centrifugation devices. Such devices are well known in the
            art.</p>
        <p id="p0051" num="0051">The term "rack" as used herein relates to a holder with one or multiple insertion areas
            for inserting one or multiple pipette tips, sample vessels, reagent containers, or reaction vessels in an
            upright position.</p>
        <p id="p0052" num="0052">In one embodiment of the embedded consumable compartment, the embedded consumable
            compartment forms an inner volume and the inner volume of the embedded consumable compartment has a
            dimension which is larger than the dimension of the consumable. And the consumable is selected from a group
            consisting of a pipette tip rack, a sample vessel rack, multiwell plate, a reagent container, or a reaction
            vessel rack. Thus, consumables can be loaded/ unloaded manually or automatically into the embedded
            consumable compartments from where the pipetting device or handling device can access the consumables for
            operating the laboratory system.</p>
        <p id="p0053" num="0053">In a further embodiment of the embedded consumable compartment, the embedded consumable
            compartment is constructed and arranged to encompass the consumable selected from a group consisting of a
            pipette tip rack, a sample vessel rack, a reagent container, or a reaction vessel rack, and a space is
            present between the embedded consumable compartment and the consumable. Accordingly, direct contact between
            the embedded consumable compartment and the consumable which may cause a contamination of the consumable is
            prevented.</p>
        <p id="p0054" num="0054">In one embodiment of the laboratory system, the laboratory system comprises more than
            one type of consumable, wherein any type of consumable comprises a specific and unique recognition feature
            such as a unique size, unique cross-section or unique surface geometry. The single base plate can be
            provided with multiple embedded consumable compartments and at least one embedded consumable compartment is
            constructed and arranged to recognize specifically said unique recognition feature of one type of
            consumable.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="16"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0055" num="0055">In a specific embodiment of the embedded consumable compartment, the embedded
            consumable compartment has at least one specific recognition element for recognizing a specific consumable.
            The term "recognition element" as used herein relates to elements, such as a guidance element formed on the
            inside of the embedded consumable compartment which fits specifically with the unique recognition feature of
            one type of consumable.</p>
        <p id="p0056" num="0056">In a specific embodiment of the laboratory system, the at least one specific
            recognition element comprises a unique surface geometry of the embedded consumable compartment. And the
            unique surface geometry of the embedded consumable compartment is complementary to a unique surface geometry
            of the specific consumable. The term "surface geometry" relates to the surface structure, more specifically
            the surface structure of the side walls of the embedded consumable compartment and consumable. A "unique
            surface geometry" is understood to be a surface geometry which is unique for a type of consumable and
            corresponding embedded consumable compartment and is substantially different from the surface geometries of
            other consumables and corresponding consumable compartments such that the consumable is specifically
            recognized by the recognition element of the corresponding embedded consumable compartment.</p>
        <p id="p0057" num="0057">In a specific embodiment of the unique surface geometry of the specific consumable, the
            unique surface geometry of the specific consumable comprises one or more recesses and/ or ridges integrally
            formed in the unique surface of the specific consumable. Thus, a specific type of consumable can only be
            loaded into a specific embedded consumable compartment. In case of manual loading of consumables into the
            laboratory instrument, this prevents the operator from loading the wrong consumable into a specific embedded
            consumable compartment, even if the consumables have the same horizontal cross section.</p>
        <p id="p0058" num="0058">In a further embodiment of the laboratory system, at least one latch-fit or snap-latch
            is located on the single base plate adjacent to the at least one embedded consumable compartment. And at
            least one corresponding counter snap-latch or latch-fit is located on the consumable in a manner to
            reversibly engage into the latch-fit or snap-latch of the single base plate.</p>
        <p id="p0059" num="0059">In an alternative embodiment of the laboratory system, the at least one latch-fit or
            snap-latch is located on the one or more electrically conductive sheets adjacent to the at least one
            through-hole and the consumable comprises the at least one corresponding counter snap-latch or latch-fit
            located in a manner to reversibly engage into the latch-fit or snap-latch adjacent of the
            <!-- EPO <DP n="17"> --> electrically conductive sheet. Thus, consumables can easily be loaded/ unloaded and
            reversibly attached to the single base for an optimal and safe operation of the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0060" num="0060">In one embodiment of the embedded sample processing compartment, the embedded sample
            processing compartment is constructed to encompass at least one sample processing device. The sample
            processing device is selected from a group consisting of a heating device, a cooling device, a mixing
            device, a separation device, an analyzing device, a storing device, or a combination thereof. And a space is
            present between the sample processing compartment and the at least one sample processing device. The side
            walls and the bottom of the embedded sample processing device may further comprise one or multiple openings
            for electrical power supply, mounting, and heat dissipation of the sample processing device.</p>
        <p id="p0061" num="0061">In a further embodiment of the embedded sample processing compartment, the embedded
            sample processing compartment forms an inner volume and the inner volume of the embedded sample processing
            compartment has a dimension which is larger than the dimension of at least one sample processing device
            selected from a group consisting of a heating device, a cooling device, a mixing device, a separation
            device, an analyzing device, a storing device, or a combination thereof. Depending on the configuration of
            the laboratory instrument, sample processing devices can be mounted in separate embedded sample processing
            compartments so that they can be shielded from each other in order to prevent a mutual negative influence.
            For example, heating and cooling devices can be mounted in separate embedded sample processing compartments
            in order to prevent any undesirable temperature exchange. But also multiple sample processing devices can be
            mounted in the same embedded sample processing compartment. For example, multiple sample processing devices
            of the same type can be accommodated in the same embedded sample processing compartment for a compact design
            of the interior of the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0062" num="0062">In one embodiment of the laboratory system, the embedded rack receiving compartment is
            constructed to receive at least one sample vessel rack or at least one reagent container rack.</p>
        <p id="p0063" num="0063">In a further embodiment of the embedded rack receiving compartment, the embedded rack
            receiving compartment forms an inner volume and the inner volume of the embedded rack receiving compartment
            has a dimension which is larger than the dimension of at least one sample vessel rack or at least one
            reagent container rack. The embedded rack receiving compartment
            <!-- EPO <DP n="18"> --> may comprise two side walls, a rear end, and an open front end forming a rack slot
            into which one or multiple sample vessel racks or reagent container racks may be inserted manually or
            automatically.</p>
        <p id="p0064" num="0064">In a more specific embodiment of the embedded rack receiving compartment, the embedded
            rack receiving compartment has a sliding surface on which at least one sample vessel rack or at least one
            reagent container rack is slidably moveable between a front end and a rear end of the rack receiving
            compartment, wherein the sliding surface comprises rack guiding elements. In order to load the rack into the
            embedded rack receiving compartment, the rack merely has to be linearly moved along the guiding elements
            towards the rear end of the embedded rack receiving compartment. Thereby, the risk of incorrectly inserting
            the rack is minimized. The sliding surface may comprise several rack guiding elements which can divide the
            sliding surface in different lanes so that multiple sample vessel racks and/or container racks can be
            loaded/ unloaded into the same embedded rack receiving compartment.</p>
        <p id="p0065" num="0065">In a specific embodiment of the laboratory system, the laboratory system further
            comprises a control device for controlling the movements of the at least one transfer system. The term
            "control device" as used herein encompasses any physical or virtual processing device configurable to
            control the laboratory system in a way that sample or sample vessel processing steps are conducted by the
            laboratory system. The control device may, for example, instruct the laboratory system to conduct
            pre-analytical, post-analytical and analytical sample processing steps. The control device may receive
            information from a data management unit regarding which steps need to be performed with a certain sample.
            The control device may, for instance, be embodied as a programmable logic controller adapted to execute a
            computer-readable program provided with instructions to perform operations of the laboratory instrument. One
            example of such an operation is to control the movements of the at least one transfer system in order to
            move the at least one pipetting device or handling device in the three-dimensional directions x, y, and z to
            a target position within the laboratory instrument. A further example of such an operation is to conduct a
            method for adjusting the positioning of at least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory
            instrument or laboratory system as described further below.</p>
        <p id="p0066" num="0066">In one embodiment of the control device, the control device is comprised by the
            laboratory instrument.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="19"> -->
        </p>
        <p id="p0067" num="0067">In another embodiment, the control device is an external device communicatively
            connected to the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0068" num="0068">The present invention also relates to a method for adjusting the positioning of at
            least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory instrument or laboratory system as described
            herein. The method comprises the following steps:
            <ol id="ol0001" compact="compact" ol-style="">
                <li>a) the at least one transfer system moves the at least one pipetting device or handling device
                    towards the at least one reference structure</li>
                <li>b) the at least one reference structure detection device of the at least one pipetting device or
                    handling device detects the at least one reference structure, wherein the at least one reference
                    structure detection device generates at least one signal upon detection of the at least one
                    reference structure and sends the at least one signal to the control device</li>
                <li>c) the control device receives the at least one signal from the at least one reference structure
                    detection device and determines position information of the at least one reference structure based
                    on the received at least one signal</li>
                <li>d) the control device compares the determined position information of the at least one reference
                    structure with predefined position information of the at least one reference structure</li>
                <li>e) the control device determines and stores a deviation between the determined position information
                    of the at least one reference structure and the predefined position information of the at least one
                    reference structure</li>
                <li>f) the control device adjusts the positioning of the at least one pipetting device or handling
                    device of the laboratory instrument or laboratory system according to the determined and stored
                    deviation between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure and
                    the predefined position information of the at least one reference structure.</li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        <p id="p0069" num="0069">During operation of the laboratory instrument, where hundreds of sample processing
            steps may be conducted per day, the accuracy of the positioning of the pipetting device or handling device
            may decrease over time which causes erroneous operations of the laboratory instrument or even damages of the
            vessels or the at least one pipetting device or handling device of the laboratory instrument. Therefore, the
            method for adjusting the positioning of the at least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory
            instrument or laboratory system should be repeated from time to time. The term "positioning" as used herein
            means that the at least one pipetting device or handling device is moved to a target position by the
            transfer system within
            <!-- EPO <DP n="20"> --> the laboratory instrument for conducting a certain sample processing step at the
            target position, wherein the target position comprises predefined position information consisting of x, y,
            and z values within the three-dimensional rectangular coordinate system of the laboratory instrument.</p>
        <p id="p0070" num="0070">As used herein, the term "adjusting" relates to a process where a deviation between
            predefined position information and actual or determined position information of at least one reference
            structure is corrected or compensated. As the transfer system moves the pipetting device or handling device
            within the laboratory instrument for positioning, this correction or compensation can be made by a new
            setting of the drives of the transfer system, wherein the new setting of the drives depends on the deviation
            between the predefined and determined position information of the at least one reference structure.</p>
        <p id="p0071" num="0071">In a specific embodiment of the method, the at least one transfer system moves the at
            least one pipetting device or handling device towards the at least one reference structure from the z
            direction, x direction, and y direction in step a), the at least one reference structure detection device
            generates at least three signals upon detection of the at least one reference structure from the z
            direction, x direction, and y direction and sends the at least three signals to the control device in step
            b), the control device receives the at least three signals from the at least one reference structure
            detection device and determines position information of the at least one reference structure based on the
            received at least three signals in step c).</p>
        <p id="p0072" num="0072">In a more specific embodiment, immediately after step e) of the disclosed method, the
            control device determines if the determined deviation between the determined position information of the at
            least one reference structure and the predefined position information of the at least one reference
            structure is within a predefined deviation range. If the determined deviation between the determined
            position information of the at least one reference structure and the predefined position information of the
            at least one reference structure is within the predefined deviation range step f) is conducted. And if the
            determined deviation between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure and
            the predefined position information of the at least one reference structure is not within the predefined
            deviation range an alert is triggered. The predefined deviation range relates to deviations for which the
            positioning of the at least one pipetting device or handling device can be adjusted by setting the drives of
            the transfer system. In the case of deviations which cannot be corrected or compensated by setting
            <!-- EPO <DP n="21"> --> the drives of the transfer system, the guide rails of the transfer system must be
            manually adjusted so that the determined position information is again aligned with the predefined position
            information of the at least one reference structure. Accordingly, the triggered alert may comprise a
            recommendation or request for visual inspection of the laboratory instrument and manual adjustment of the
            transfer system.</p>
        <p id="p0073" num="0073">In one embodiment of the laboratory system as described herein, said control device is
            adapted to control the method as described herein.</p>
        <p id="p0074" num="0074">Further disclosed and proposed is a computer program including computer-executable
            instructions for performing the method according to the present invention in one or more of the embodiments
            enclosed herein when the program is executed on the control device. Specifically, the computer program may
            be stored on a computer-readable data carrier. Thus, specifically, one, more than one or even all of method
            steps as indicated above may be performed by using the control device, preferably by using the computer
            program.</p>
        <p id="p0075" num="0075">Further disclosed and proposed is a computer program product having program code means
            in order to perform the method disclosed herein in one or more of the embodiments enclosed herein when the
            program is executed on a control device. Specifically, the program code means may be stored on a
            computer-readable data carrier.</p>
        <p id="p0076" num="0076">Referring to the computer-implemented aspects of the invention, one or more of the
            method steps or even all of the method steps of the method according to one or more of the embodiments
            disclosed herein may be performed by using a control device. Thus, generally, any of the method steps
            including provision and/or manipulation of information or data may be performed by using a control device.
            <!-- EPO <DP n="22"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0005"><b><u>Short description of the figures</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0077" num="0077">
            <ul id="ul0002" list-style="none">
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0001"><b>Fig. 1</b></figref> provides a perspective view of the laboratory
                    instrument as described herein.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig. 2</b></figref> shows an electrically conductive element, a single base
                    plate, and the electrically conductive element mounted on the single base plate as described herein.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0003"><b>Fig. 3</b></figref> shows a cross section of the single base plate and the
                    electrically conductive element as described herein.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0004"><b>Fig. 4</b></figref> provides a top view of the single base plate and the
                    electrically conductive element as described herein.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0005"><b>Fig. 5</b></figref> provides a perspective view of the laboratory system as
                    described herein.
                </li>
                <li>
                    <figref idref="f0006"><b>Fig. 6</b></figref> depicts flowcharts of the method for adjusting the
                    positioning of at least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory system as described
                    herein.
                </li>
            </ul><!-- EPO <DP n="23"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0006"><b><u>Detailed description of the figures</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0078" num="0078">
            <figref idref="f0001"><b>Fig. 1</b></figref> shows a perspective view of the laboratory instrument (10) as
            described herein. As illustrated, the laboratory instrument (10) comprises a single base plate (12). The
            single base plate (12) comprises embedded compartments (14) which are further specified in <figref
                idref="f0002"><b>Fig 2</b></figref><b>.</b> The laboratory instrument (10) has also a housing (26)
            comprising a frame (28). It is to be noted that the hood of the laboratory instrument (10) is omitted in
            <figref idref="f0001">Fig.1</figref> in order to improve the visibility of the interior of the laboratory
            instrument. The single base plate (12) is mounted on the frame (28) within the laboratory instrument (10).
            As further shown in <figref idref="f0001">Fig. 1</figref>, the laboratory instrument comprises a pipetting
            device (60) equipped with one reference structure detection device (62). In the shown embodiment, the
            reference structure detection device (62) is a conductive pipette tip. The laboratory instrument (10) has
            also a transfer system (64) which is connected to the pipetting device (60). In the shown embodiment, the
            laboratory instrument (10) further comprises a control device (76) for controlling the movements of the
            transfer system (64). As schematically illustrated, the laboratory instrument has a three-dimensional
            rectangular coordinate system comprising a x direction, y direction, and z direction. The transfer system
            (64) is constructed to move the pipetting device (60) in the three-dimensional directions x, y, and z within
            the laboratory instrument. In the shown embodiment, the laboratory instrument further comprises an
            electrically conductive element (48) consisting of two electrically conductive sheets (49) which are mounted
            on the single base plate (12).
        </p>
        <p id="p0079" num="0079">
            <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig. 2</b></figref> shows the single base plate (12) of the laboratory instrument
            in an isolated view (<figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2B</figref>), an electrically conductive element (48) in an
            isolated view (<figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2A</figref>), and the single base plate (12) of the laboratory
            instrument on which the electrically conductive element (48) is mounted (<figref idref="f0002">Fig. 2C
            </figref>). As shown in <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig.2B</b></figref> the single base plate (12) which
            consists of a single piece comprises five embedded consumable compartments (16), two embedded sample
            processing compartments (18), an embedded waste compartment (20), an embedded activation device compartment
            (22), and one embedded rack receiving compartment (24). The single base plate (12) further comprises
            integrated support elements such as a cable channel (40), an air channel (42), a display frame (44), and an
            instrument interlock module (46). <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig. 2A</b></figref> shows an electrically
            conductive element (48) consisting of two electrically conductive sheets (49) provided with through-holes
            (52). In the shown embodiment, at least one of the through-holes
            <!-- EPO <DP n="24"> --> (52) is a reference structure (50). However, the other through-holes (52) can also
            be used as additional reference structures if required. As depicted in <figref idref="f0002"><b>Fig.2C</b>
            </figref> the two electrically conductive sheets (49) can be mounted on the single base plate (12), wherein
            the through-holes (52) of the electrically conductive sheets (49) are aligned with the open tops (38) of the
            embedded consumable compartments (16), embedded sample processing compartments (18), embedded waste
            compartment (20), and embedded activation device compartment (22) of the single base plate (12). As further
            shown, an activation device (47) is accommodated in the embedded activation device compartment (22).
        </p>
        <p id="p0080" num="0080">
            <figref idref="f0003"><b>Fig. 3</b></figref> shows a cross section of the single base plate (12), embedded
            compartment (14) and electrically conductive sheet (49). The shown embedded compartment (14) comprises side
            walls (34), a closed bottom (36), and an open top (38) which encompass an inner volume (35) of the embedded
            compartment (14). As further shown the embedded compartment (14) comprises rounded corners (30) and rounded
            edges (32). The electrically conductive sheet (49) is mounted on the single base plate (12) with screws
            (56). In the shown embodiment, the screws (56) for mounting the electrically conductive sheet is a shoulder
            screw for a floating mounting of the electrically conductive sheet (49) on the single base plate (12).
        </p>
        <p id="p0081" num="0081">
            <figref idref="f0004"><b>Fig. 4</b></figref> provides a top view of the single base plate (12) and the
            electrically conductive sheets (49) which are mounted on the single base plate with shoulder screws (56) and
            fixed points (58). As shown in <figref idref="f0004">Fig. 4</figref>, the electrically conductive sheets
            (49) comprise snap-latches (54) located adjacent to the through-holes which are aligned with the open tops
            of the embedded consumable compartments (16) and embedded waste compartment (20) for clipping the
            consumables and waste containers. The shown rack receiving compartment (24) has a sliding surface (72) which
            comprises three rack guiding elements (74). The three guiding elements divide the sliding surface (72) in
            two lanes so that sample vessel racks as well as reagent container racks can be slidably moved between the
            front end and a rear end of the rack receiving compartment (24) in order to load/ unload sample vessel racks
            and reagent container racks into the same embedded rack receiving compartment (24).
        </p>
        <p id="p0082" num="0082">
            <figref idref="f0005"><b>Fig. 5</b></figref> provides a perspective view of the laboratory system (65) as
            described herein. The shown laboratory system (65) comprises a laboratory instrument (10) with a consumable
            (66) in form of a pipette tip rack. The shown laboratory system (65) further comprises sample processing
            <!-- EPO <DP n="25"> --> devices (68) in form of three separation and heating devices and one cooling
            device. The shown laboratory system (65) further comprises one sample vessel rack (69) and one reagent
            container rack (70) which are in the embedded rack receiving compartment (24). Furthermore, the shown
            laboratory system (65) comprises also a waste rack (71) in form of a tip waste rack for disposing used
            pipette tips. To control the movement of the transfer system, the laboratory system comprises a control
            device (76).
        </p>
        <p id="p0083" num="0083">
            <figref idref="f0006"><b>Fig. 6A</b></figref> shows a flowchart of the method for adjusting the positioning
            of at least one pipetting device or handling device of a laboratory instrument or laboratory system. Before
            the method is initiated, the operator has to make sure that no consumables (66), waste racks (71), sample
            vessel racks (69) or reagent container racks (70) prevent the accessibility to the at least one reference
            structure (50). In step a) (78) of the method the at least one transfer system (64) moves the pipetting
            device (60) or handling device towards the at least one reference structure (50). In step b) (80) of the
            method the at least one reference structure detection device (62) of the at least one pipetting device (60)
            or handling device detects the at least one reference structure (50) and the at least one reference
            structure detection device (62) generates at least one signal upon detection of the at least one reference
            structure (50). And the at least one signal is send to the control device (76). In step c) (82) of the
            method the control device (76) receives the at least one signal from the at least one reference structure
            detection device (62) and determines position information of the at least one reference structure (50) based
            on the received at least one signal. Afterwards, the control device (76) compares the determined position
            information of the at least reference structure (50) with predefined position information of the least one
            reference structure (50) in step d) (84) of the method. In step e) (86) of the method the control device
            (76) determines and stores the deviation between the determined position information of the at least one
            reference structure (50) and the predefined position information of the at least one reference structure
            (50). According to the determined and stored deviation between the determined position information of the at
            least one reference structure (50) and the predefined position information of the at least one reference
            structure (50), the control device adjusts the positioning of the at least one pipetting device (60) or
            handling device in step f) (88) of the method. As shown in <figref idref="f0006"><b>Fig. 6B</b></figref>
            <b>,</b> one embodiment of the method can comprise two additional steps (90, 92). In the first additional
            step (90) which is conducted after step e) (86) of the method, the control device (76) determines if the
            determined deviation between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure
            (50) and the predefined position information of the at least
            <!-- EPO <DP n="26"> --> one reference structure (50) is within a predefined deviation range. If the
            determined deviation between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure and
            the predefined position information of the at least one reference structure is within the predefined
            deviation range step f) (88) of the method is conducted. And if the determined deviation between the
            determined position information of the at least one reference structure and the predefined position
            information of the at least one reference structure is not within the predefined deviation range an alert is
            triggered in the second additional step (92).
            <!-- EPO <DP n="27"> -->
        </p>
        <heading id="h0007"><b><u>List of reference numbers</u></b></heading>
        <p id="p0084" num="0084">
            <dl id="dl0001" compact="compact">
                <dt>10</dt>
                <dd>laboratory instrument</dd>
                <dt>12</dt>
                <dd>single base plate</dd>
                <dt>14</dt>
                <dd>embedded compartment</dd>
                <dt>16</dt>
                <dd>embedded consumable compartment</dd>
                <dt>18</dt>
                <dd>embedded sample processing compartment</dd>
                <dt>20</dt>
                <dd>embedded waste compartment</dd>
                <dt>22</dt>
                <dd>embedded activation device compartment</dd>
                <dt>24</dt>
                <dd>embedded rack receiving compartment</dd>
                <dt>26</dt>
                <dd>housing</dd>
                <dt>28</dt>
                <dd>frame</dd>
                <dt>30</dt>
                <dd>rounded corner</dd>
                <dt>32</dt>
                <dd>rounded edge</dd>
                <dt>34</dt>
                <dd>side wall</dd>
                <dt>35</dt>
                <dd>inner volume</dd>
                <dt>36</dt>
                <dd>closed bottom</dd>
                <dt>38</dt>
                <dd>open top</dd>
                <dt>40</dt>
                <dd>cable channel</dd>
                <dt>42</dt>
                <dd>air channel</dd>
                <dt>44</dt>
                <dd>display frame</dd>
                <dt>46</dt>
                <dd>instrument interlock module</dd>
                <dt>47</dt>
                <dd>activation device</dd>
                <dt>48</dt>
                <dd>electrically conductive element</dd>
                <dt>49</dt>
                <dd>electrically conductive sheet</dd>
                <dt>50</dt>
                <dd>reference structure</dd>
                <dt>52</dt>
                <dd>through-hole</dd>
                <dt>54</dt>
                <dd>snap-latch or latch-fit</dd>
                <dt>56</dt>
                <dd>screw</dd>
                <dt>58</dt>
                <dd>fixed-point</dd>
                <dt>60</dt>
                <dd>pipetting device</dd>
                <dt>62</dt>
                <dd>reference structure detection device</dd>
                <dt>64</dt>
                <dd>transfer system
                    <!-- EPO <DP n="28"> -->
                </dd>
                <dt>65</dt>
                <dd>laboratory system</dd>
                <dt>66</dt>
                <dd>consumable</dd>
                <dt>68</dt>
                <dd>sample processing device</dd>
                <dt>69</dt>
                <dd>sample vessel rack</dd>
                <dt>70</dt>
                <dd>reagent container rack</dd>
                <dt>71</dt>
                <dd>waste rack</dd>
                <dt>72</dt>
                <dd>sliding surface</dd>
                <dt>74</dt>
                <dd>guiding elements</dd>
                <dt>76</dt>
                <dd>control device</dd>
                <dt>78</dt>
                <dd>step a of the method</dd>
                <dt>80</dt>
                <dd>step b of the method</dd>
                <dt>82</dt>
                <dd>step c of the method</dd>
                <dt>84</dt>
                <dd>step d of the method</dd>
                <dt>86</dt>
                <dd>step e of the method</dd>
                <dt>88</dt>
                <dd>step f of the method</dd>
                <dt>90</dt>
                <dd>first additional step of the method</dd>
                <dt>92</dt>
                <dd>second additional step of the method</dd>
            </dl>
        </p>
    </description>
    <claims id="claims01" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="29"> -->
        <claim id="c-en-0001" num="0001">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10), comprising:
                <claim-text>- a single base plate (12), wherein the single base plate comprises at least one embedded
                    compartment (14), wherein at least one of said embedded compartment is selected from a group
                    consisting of an embedded consumable compartment (16), an embedded sample processing compartment
                    (18), an embedded waste compartment (20), an embedded activation device compartment (22), an
                    embedded rack receiving compartment (24), or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0002" num="0002">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claim 1, wherein the single base plate is made of a
                thermoplastic or duroplastic polymer.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0003" num="0003">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claims 1 or 2, wherein the single base plate is an
                injection molding plate.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0004" num="0004">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 3, wherein the at least one
                embedded compartment (14) comprises rounded corners (30) or rounded edges (32) or a combination thereof.
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0005" num="0005">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 4, wherein the single base plate
                further comprises at least one embedded support element, wherein at least one of said embedded support
                element is selected from a group consisting of a cable channel (40), an air channel (42), a display
                frame (44), an identification device or sensor holder, an instrument interlock module (46), a latch-fit
                or snap-latch, or a combination thereof.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0006" num="0006">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 5, additionally comprising:
                <claim-text>- at least one electrically conductive element (48), wherein the at least one electrically
                    conductive element is mounted on the single base plate (12).</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0007" num="0007">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claim 6, wherein the electrically conductive element
                comprises at least one reference structure (50).
                <!-- EPO <DP n="30"> -->
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0008" num="0008">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claims 6 or 7, wherein the at least one electrically
                conductive element comprises one or more electrically conductive sheets (49), wherein at least one of
                the one or more electrically conductive sheets comprises at least one through-hole (52), wherein the at
                least one through-hole is aligned with the open top of at least one embedded compartment (38).
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0009" num="0009">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claim 8, wherein the at least one through-hole (52) is
                the least one reference structure (50).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0010" num="0010">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claims 8 or 9, wherein said one or more electrically
                conductive sheets are mounted on the single base plate with one or more screws (56).</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0011" num="0011">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to claim 11, wherein the one or more screws are shoulder
                screws (56), wherein the one or more conductive sheets are additionally mounted with at least one
                fixed-point (58) on the single base plate.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0012" num="0012">
            <claim-text>Laboratory instrument (10) according to any of the claims 1 to 11, additionally comprising:
                <claim-text>- at least one pipetting device (60) or handling device, wherein the at least one pipetting
                    device (60) or handling device comprises at least one reference structure detection device (62)
                </claim-text>
                <claim-text>- at least one transfer system (64), wherein the at least one transfer system is connected
                    to the at least one pipetting device or handling device, wherein the at least one transfer system is
                    constructed to move the at least one pipetting device or handling device in the three-dimensional
                    directions within the laboratory instrument.</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0013" num="0013">
            <claim-text>Laboratory system, comprising:
                <claim-text>- a laboratory instrument according to any of the claims 1 to 12</claim-text>
                <claim-text>- at least one consumable (66) or at least one sample processing device (68) or at least one
                    rack (70) or a combination thereof.</claim-text><!-- EPO <DP n="31"> -->
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0014" num="0014">
            <claim-text>A laboratory system according to claim 13, further comprising a control device (76) for
                controlling the movements of the at least one transfer system.</claim-text>
        </claim>
        <claim id="c-en-0015" num="0015">
            <claim-text>Method for adjusting the positioning of at least one pipetting device or handling device of a
                laboratory instrument or laboratory system according to any one of claims 7 to 14, comprising the
                following steps:
                <claim-text>a) the at least one transfer system (64) moves the at least one pipetting device (60) or
                    handling device towards the at least one reference structure (50)</claim-text>
                <claim-text>b) the at least one reference structure detection device (62) of the at least one pipetting
                    device (60) or handling device detects the at least one reference structure (50), wherein the at
                    least one reference structure detection device (62) generates at least one signal upon detection of
                    the at least one reference structure (50) and sends the at least one signal to the control device
                    (76)</claim-text>
                <claim-text>c) the control device (76) receives the at least one signal from the at least one reference
                    structure detection device (62) and determines position information of the at least one reference
                    structure (50) based on the received at least one signal</claim-text>
                <claim-text>d) the control device (76) compares the determined position information of the at least one
                    reference structure (50) with predefined position information of the at least one reference
                    structure (50)</claim-text>
                <claim-text>e) the control device (76) determines and stores a deviation between the determined position
                    information of the at least one reference structure (50) and the predefined position information of
                    the at least one reference structure (50)</claim-text>
                <claim-text>f) the control device adjusts the positioning of the at least one pipetting device or
                    handling device of the laboratory instrument or laboratory system according to the determined and
                    stored deviation between the determined position information of the at least one reference structure
                    and the predefined position information of the at least one reference structure.</claim-text>
            </claim-text>
        </claim>
    </claims>
    <drawings id="draw" lang="en">
        <!-- EPO <DP n="32"> -->
        <figure id="f0001" num="1"><img id="if0001" file="imgf0001.tif" wi="156" he="230" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="33"> -->
        <figure id="f0002" num="2,2A,2B,2C"><img id="if0002" file="imgf0002.tif" wi="143" he="233" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="34"> -->
        <figure id="f0003" num="3"><img id="if0003" file="imgf0003.tif" wi="145" he="198" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="35"> -->
        <figure id="f0004" num="4"><img id="if0004" file="imgf0004.tif" wi="155" he="232" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="36"> -->
        <figure id="f0005" num="5"><img id="if0005" file="imgf0005.tif" wi="152" he="233" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure><!-- EPO <DP n="37"> -->
        <figure id="f0006" num="6,6A,6B"><img id="if0006" file="imgf0006.tif" wi="145" he="233" img-content="drawing"
                img-format="tif" /></figure>
    </drawings>
    <search-report-data id="srep" lang="en" srep-office="EP" date-produced="">
        <doc-page id="srep0001" file="srep0001.tif" wi="157" he="233" type="tif" />
        <doc-page id="srep0002" file="srep0002.tif" wi="155" he="233" type="tif" />
    </search-report-data>
    <search-report-data date-produced="20180119" id="srepxml" lang="en" srep-office="EP" srep-type="ep-sr" status="n">
        <!--
 The search report data in XML is provided for the users' convenience only. It might differ from the search report of the PDF document, which contains the officially published data. The EPO disclaims any liability for incorrect or incomplete data in the XML for search reports.
 -->

        <srep-info>
            <file-reference-id>P34267-EP-TB</file-reference-id>
            <application-reference>
                <document-id>
                    <country>EP</country>
                    <doc-number>17185386.4</doc-number>
                </document-id>
            </application-reference>
            <applicant-name>
                <name>Roche Diagnostics GmbH</name>
            </applicant-name>
            <srep-established srep-established="yes" />
            <srep-invention-title title-approval="yes" />
            <srep-abstract abs-approval="yes" />
            <srep-figure-to-publish figinfo="by-applicant">
                <figure-to-publish>
                    <fig-number>1</fig-number>
                </figure-to-publish>
            </srep-figure-to-publish>
            <srep-info-admin>
                <srep-office>
                    <addressbook><text>DH</text></addressbook>
                </srep-office>
                <date-search-report-mailed>
                    <date>20180126</date>
                </date-search-report-mailed>
            </srep-info-admin>
        </srep-info>
        <srep-for-pub>
            <srep-fields-searched>
                <minimum-documentation>
                    <classifications-ipcr>
                        <classification-ipcr><text>B01L</text></classification-ipcr>
                        <classification-ipcr><text>G01N</text></classification-ipcr>
                    </classifications-ipcr>
                </minimum-documentation>
            </srep-fields-searched>
            <srep-citations>
                <citation id="sr-cit0001">
                    <patcit dnum="US2005025673A1" id="sr-pcit0001"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US2005025673&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2005025673</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <name>SHIMEI THOMAS M [US]</name>
                            <date>20050203</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>X</category>
                    <rel-claims>1-5,13</rel-claims>
                    <category>Y</category>
                    <rel-claims>6-12,14,15</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* figures 1,7 *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* paragraphs [0034], [0039] *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
                <citation id="sr-cit0002">
                    <patcit dnum="US5512247A" id="sr-pcit0002"
                        url="http://v3.espacenet.com/textdoc?DB=EPODOC&amp;IDX=US5512247&amp;CY=ep">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5512247</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <name>BONACINA GUIDO [CH] ET AL</name>
                            <date>19960430</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <category>Y</category>
                    <rel-claims>6-12,14,15</rel-claims>
                    <rel-passage>
                        <passage>* figures 1,2 *</passage>
                        <passage>* column 3, line 21 - column 6, line 9 *</passage>
                        <passage>* claim 1 *</passage>
                    </rel-passage>
                </citation>
            </srep-citations>
            <srep-admin>
                <examiners>
                    <primary-examiner>
                        <name>Rasmusson, Marcus</name>
                    </primary-examiner>
                </examiners>
                <srep-office>
                    <addressbook><text>The Hague</text></addressbook>
                </srep-office>
                <date-search-completed>
                    <date>20180119</date>
                </date-search-completed>
            </srep-admin>
            <!--							The annex lists the patent family members relating to the patent documents cited in the above mentioned European search report.							The members are as contained in the European Patent Office EDP file on							The European Patent Office is in no way liable for these particulars which are merely given for the purpose of information.							For more details about this annex : see Official Journal of the European Patent Office, No 12/82						-->
            <srep-patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2005025673</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20050203</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AT</country>
                            <doc-number>250978</doc-number>
                            <kind>T</kind>
                            <date>20031015</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AT</country>
                            <doc-number>446141</doc-number>
                            <kind>T</kind>
                            <date>20091115</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AU</country>
                            <doc-number>746039</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>20020411</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CA</country>
                            <doc-number>2306879</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19990529</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CA</country>
                            <doc-number>2594172</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19990529</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>DE</country>
                            <doc-number>69818702</doc-number>
                            <kind>T2</kind>
                            <date>20040722</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>DK</country>
                            <doc-number>1030736</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20040126</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1030736</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>20000830</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>1340982</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>20030903</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>ES</country>
                            <doc-number>2209222</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20040616</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>4163382</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>20081008</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>2001523812</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>20011127</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>6254826</doc-number>
                            <kind>B1</kind>
                            <date>20010703</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2001012492</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20010809</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2001016178</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20010823</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>2005025673</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>20050203</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>9925476</doc-number>
                            <kind>A2</kind>
                            <date>19990527</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                </patent-family>
                <patent-family>
                    <priority-application>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5512247</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19960430</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </priority-application>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>AT</country>
                            <doc-number>210273</doc-number>
                            <kind>T</kind>
                            <date>20011215</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>CA</country>
                            <doc-number>2147737</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19951103</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>DE</country>
                            <doc-number>59509892</doc-number>
                            <kind>D1</kind>
                            <date>20020117</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>EP</country>
                            <doc-number>0681160</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                            <date>19951108</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>ES</country>
                            <doc-number>2167383</doc-number>
                            <kind>T3</kind>
                            <date>20020516</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>2799301</doc-number>
                            <kind>B2</kind>
                            <date>19980917</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>JP</country>
                            <doc-number>H0843403</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19960216</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                    <family-member>
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>5512247</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                            <date>19960430</date>
                        </document-id>
                    </family-member>
                </patent-family>
            </srep-patent-family>
        </srep-for-pub>
    </search-report-data>
    <ep-reference-list id="ref-list">
        <heading id="ref-h0001"><b>REFERENCES CITED IN THE DESCRIPTION</b></heading>
        <p id="ref-p0001" num=""><i>This list of references cited by the applicant is for the reader's convenience only.
                It does not form part of the European patent document. Even though great care has been taken in
                compiling the references, errors or omissions cannot be excluded and the EPO disclaims all liability in
                this regard.</i></p>
        <heading id="ref-h0002"><b>Patent documents cited in the description</b></heading>
        <p id="ref-p0002" num="">
            <ul id="ref-ul0001" list-style="bullet">
                <li>
                    <patcit id="ref-pcit0001" dnum="US20140263879A1">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>20140263879</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <crossref idref="pcit0001">[0005]</crossref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <patcit id="ref-pcit0002" dnum="US20090090198A1">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>US</country>
                            <doc-number>20090090198</doc-number>
                            <kind>A1</kind>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <crossref idref="pcit0002">[0005]</crossref>
                </li>
                <li>
                    <patcit id="ref-pcit0003" dnum="WO2017064089A">
                        <document-id>
                            <country>WO</country>
                            <doc-number>2017064089</doc-number>
                            <kind>A</kind>
                        </document-id>
                    </patcit>
                    <crossref idref="pcit0003">[0018]</crossref>
                </li>
            </ul>
        </p>
    </ep-reference-list>
</ep-patent-document>